A fancy ladder

Day 00513: Monday, 2016 August 01

Today was mostly just another day of sorting various items into categories preparation to go through each category and figure out what to keep and not. At the end of the day though, we also stopped at a hardware store and picked up an expensive, fancy ladder. We need it to get up on the roof and remove all the moss that has grown up there. While we're at it, we can also clean out the gutters. It turns out that my mother's always wanted one of these ladders, so there was more to this pricey purchase than just a one-time job. I offered to do the work on the roof myself before we bought the thing, even mentioning that I could go out the back window and wouldn't need a ladder at all. However, it seems that the two of us will instead be taking shifts up there. This will be happening tomorrow.

Also tomorrow, I have a mattress to move and a bunch of boxes to shuffle. Cyrus' mattress is bad, so we're taking that to somewhere that handles mattress recycling. We need to get several large items off of the back porch, so we need a place in the house to put them. As it would be needless effort to drag these object deep into the house and doing such would also create more work for when the objects need to be removed again, I'm clearing out the room just off the entryway that we stored many of the boxes in. My mother said that we should move them into Vanessa's bedroom, but there's really no space in there for a massive amount of unsorted boxes. Instead, I'll probably move the small piles of sorted items into Vanessa's room and put the massive box pile in my own bedroom. It's a bit further to move the boxes, but I think that it's a more feasible plan. I really should start moving things tonight, but I'm kind of tired and not really feeling up to the job.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

A fallen tree and berry vines

Day 00514: Tuesday, 2016 August 02

In my tiredness last night, I kind of jumbled some things in my head before writing my journal entry. The plan was never for me to go up on the roof to de-moss; my mother fears that my coordination is lacking and that I could fall off and break something and/or die. My mother's a bit hesitant to go up there themselves though, and is now considering hiring someone to do it for us. Instead of taking shifts on roof work, the actual plan was to tack shifts with the safer power washer, using it to clean the porches.

My mother stopped me from sorting boxes once I had the room just off the entryway about half cleared out. They'd managed to consolidate a lot of stuff in the living room, which is right near the back door. Instead of moving the things on the back porch to the room off the entryway, we moved them into the living room. While sorting boxes from the room off the entryway, I kept finding boxes of books, but our book room was too crowded at first to accept more boxes, so I also spent a lot of time reorganizing those boxes to make room for more.

I hacked a bit at the fallen tree and berry vines in the back yard, hoping to make progress at cleaning that up. It probably predates this journal, but the tree in our back yard fell over one winter when it was overburdened by ice, a strange occurrence here in Springfield. With the tree now taking up most of our half of the yard, blackberry vines started using the tree as a bracing structure for their own growth. The entirety of our half of the back yard is filled with unpassable plantlife and has been for quite a while. While we thought that the thick layers of ice had killed the fallen tree, we found out that spring that it hadn't, and while the tree is clearly on its side, it continues to thrive. With no way to right it though, that tree's going to have to be removed in preparation for selling the house. As I hacked at the vines and tree, my mother reminded me of the pit present in the yard as well. That pit was to be made into a pond, but that didn't work out. Now as we prepare to sell the house, the pit will need to be filled in. My mother says that the pit prevents us from keeping the yard maintained, as we can't just mow it to keep the berry vines at bay. They say that we probably need to hire someone to clear out this mess as well, as attacking vines that spring out of the pit isn't feasible and if we manage to hack up the tree, we've got nowhere to haul it (or the vines) off to. My efforts futile, I stopped hacking at the vines fairly soon.

While I was still trying to make progress on the yard, I spotted our old latter, which was on the porch just off my mother's bedroom, but had become obscured by the fallen tree. My mother was a bit frustrated to have bought the new ladder when we still had one available. Ostensibly, this ladder wasn't the same kind though, as previously, my mother mentioned having always wanted one of this type. Then again, my assumptions could be wrong, as my mother is known for forgetfulness.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Countdown to domain expiration

Day 00515: Wednesday, 2016 August 03

I spent most of the day power washing the back porch. I wasn't quite able to finish though, as my mother had insisted that I secretly borrow our father's hose for the job and wanted it returned before they got home to notice. I will need to finish the job tomorrow.

The Samsung GT-I727 made it back to the seller today and they said that they'll issue a refund within five days. That mess is finally taken care of, though it'd be nice if they'd actually been able to send the GT-I3100 that they'd promised on the product page. Additionally, we've been having issues trying to keep my mother's computer connected to the Internet through the carrier-provided device. If the device wasn't blocking basic tethering, it'd be easy to set up properly, but as-is, I had to hack together a solution involving several components, any of which could be the cause of the issue. I finally managed to stabilize the connection, actually bypassing that strange HTTP proxy application that I added to the device the other day to set up the connection. That application was important, as the setup instructions provided the information needed to connect to an HTTP proxy on the device from the desktop machine using ADB, but other than that, isn't needed. The fact is, Orbot has a built-in, secret HTTP proxy, so as long as you know that that proxy is running on port 8118, you don't need a second HTTP proxy to be installed. I simply forwarded a desktop port to that mobile port directly.

It seems that the SuperTux bug that I reported the other day has been fixed. Additionally, I've been sent a reminder that //ystyst.mp. is expiring in sixty days. The registry will probably contact me a few more times about this as time progresses, but I have no intention of renewing it. That domain was only purchased in error.

My mother dropped me off at the laundromat to wash our clothes, then took off with Vanessa to do other things while I waited, as there was no point in the three of us all wasting time there. I probably should have taken the opportunity to do something productive on my laptop, but I don't seem to have any motivation to do such when I'm there. The atmosphere there doesn't lend itself well to productivity. Tomorrow, my mother has another job interview tomorrow, this time in Salem, so I'll try to be more productive while they're away.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.1 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Rescuing a crushed hose, cleaning an upholstered chair, and attempting to set up a Wi-Fi dongle

Day 00516: Thursday, 2016 August 04

I am not comfortable borrowing items from people without their knowledge and without their permission. I spotted a hose trapped under the fallen tree and vines in the back yard yesterday while I was power washing, so I made it my goal for the day to rescue the hose and prevent the further need to jack my father's hose. It turns out that a large branch that was supporting the tree was lying right on top of the hose, crushing it, so I feared that the hose would have become too leaky to be of any good. Once the hose was free, I hooked it up to the power washer to find out how damaged the hose actually was, and found that it'd survived remarkably well; the water pressure restored the hose's rightful shape and no visible leaking occurred. I think that the tree actually protected the hose more than it harmed it, blocking the sun's destructive rays from hitting the hose nearly as much as they otherwise would have. With everything working correctly, I finished power washing the back porch.

Vanessa cut themself shaving, but didn't notice until they'd bled on our mother's new second-hand chair. They tried to clean it off, but that didn't co as expected, as attempting to clean off the blood spots only made them that much larger. They had me take a look, and much to our surprise, the upholstered chair was actually covered in an unnoticeable layer of dirt. The large spots on the chair weren't smeared blood - they were clean spots! Vanessa worried that our mother might have wanted the chair to be the color that they'd purchased the chair as, but neither of us had any way to revert the chair to it's former state. I scrubbed the rest of the chair to make the whole thing clean, thereby removing the spots. As I though, our mother wasn't upset about the color change when they got home, but they also didn't go take a look at it. Still, clean is better than dirty, so I never expected there to be a problem.

Our mother liked the school in Salem. They really want to live in Salem, saying that Salem has the same feel as Springfield but is a bit further from our father.

Vanessa, our mother, and I headed to the store to get a Wi-Fi dongle for our mother, as apparently, they apparently understand the concept of Wi-Fi dongles better than Wi-Fi cards. The Wi-Fi card is of course a much better option, as that option doesn't involve blocking the laptop's one and only USB port and the Wi-Fi card slot probably offers better speeds than the USB port, but once our mother gets strange ideas in their head, there's no arguing with them. Quite frankly, I'm not the one dealing with the machine either, so it's not my problem if my mother wants to go with the more frustrating option. Once we had it home, I attempted to set up the Wi-Fi dongle for them, but that didn't go well. First, the Wi-Fi dongle insisted that it required a Windows update before it'd support encrypted Wi-Fi networks. This machine's running Windows XP, I'm not even sure if such an update even still exists. After much frustration, I managed to get Java and Android tools set up, but ADB refused to cooperate. With no pseudo-tethering and no Wi-Fi, I wasn't able to even try to update the machine and had to give up for the night. I also tried setting up my own supposedly-free Wi-Fi dongle on the machine, but even with the driver installed, the machine doesn't seem to recognize the hardware. Our mother says that there's an open Wi-Fi access point at the corner of our block, so I'll try using it to update the machine in the morning.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Trust

Day 00517: Friday, 2016 August 05

I tried to use the Wi-Fi access point at the corner of our block to update my mother's laptop, but the laptop couldn't connect. It saw the list of available access points, but after telling it to connect to one, it'd just hang of a few minutes. The laptop was usable during this time, it just wasn't connected to the network yet. After several minutes had passed, the laptop would inform me that the connection attempt had failed. I kept trying until the battery power was nearly depleted, but it was a futile effort. Either the Wi-Fi dongle wasn't actually compatible with the machine or the operating system update was required not only for use with encrypted networks, but open networks as well.

Our mother left for a teachers' conference and will return on Sunday. While they were away, I was supposed to return the Wi-Fi dongle to the store for them, but that didn't go as planned. Vanessa and I searched for the receipt, but our mother'd taken the receipt with them! I'd need to wait until they returned with it to return the dongle or they'd need to return it when they got back.

Today should have been a very productive day, but instead, I took a break and spent most of the day loafing around. Near the end of the day, Vanessa and I went out to pick up sandwiches, then sat on one of the bleachers at a nearby school to enjoy eating them outside. We talked, and Vanessa confided in me about things that they don't feel comfortable discussing with most people, as these things have a way of finding their way back to our not-very-understanding mother. It's nice to know that I'm one of the two people that Vanessa trusts enough to to discuss these things with. The other party will remain unnamed so that they aren't pressured into exposing Vanessa's secrets if this journal entry is ever read by those that would try to harm Vanessa by involving our mother.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.1 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Replying to Bandcamp

Day 00518: Saturday, 2016 August 06

Like yesterday, today should have been productive, but it really wasn't. Instead, Vanessa and I went on a scavenger hunt. We found all but one of the items on our list, and it wasn't even the one we were expecting not to find. Vanessa and I did get some work done today though; we cleaned up the front lawn a bit.

My laptop's power cord is taped beyond recognition from all the repairs I've made on it as it's broken down. Today, it outright died, but rather than try to tape it back together and fix it, I decided to let it go. I pulled out one of my spare cords, but it makes scary electrical noises when plugged into the wall! A third cord looked too frayed, so I didn't even bother with that one. Lastly, I found the cord that I'd sent with my mother when they borrowed my laptop; it looks to be in great condition, but it's the last power cord that I have for this machine. I need to get at least one spare to have on hand for when this one inevitably gives up the ghost.

I sent out an email today, forgetting that my mail provider's server wasn't allowing me to send mail for some reason. The problem seems to have been cleared up though, as mail is going through just fine now, so I sent my belated response to the Bandcamp support team. They had told me that I should bypass my proxy when dealing with the Bandcamp website to clear up the invalid VAT charges. The nerve! What makes them think that their website is somehow above other websites and somehow deserves to have proxyless connections made to it? So many people seem to think that rather than fixing the problems on their websites, they should simply instruct people not to use proxies. They continued on to explain that in addition to the IP address location detection, they use the address associated with one's PayPal account and the location information provided on one's profile. In my letter back to them today, I apologized for the delay, explained that my email provider's server was having issues when I'd received their letter, and that because my mobile had been stolen, I wasn't able to get through my email provider's two-factor authentication mechanism and was unable to investigate that problem. I then told them my usual story about the network administrator setting up the proxy on the Wi-Fi router level, claiming that I cannot bypass it. This is of course untrue, but this story prevents people from continuing to insist that that I drop the proxy, as they think that I can't. I informed them of my dealings with PayPal and why I don't use an account to make a purchase, and of course that if they ever offer a non-PayPal payment processor as an option, I most likely won't be dealing with PayPal anymore at all, account or no account. Lastly, I explained that the problem with the profile location setting is that it's visible to everyone that views the profile; it's not used only for calculating VAT charges. As I told them, next time that I have the issue, I'll try setting my profile location temporarily, making the purchase, then setting it back, but permanently setting it to my location is a bad idea. That solution is less than ideal, but if it works, it works, and should be quicker than waiting for Tor to switch exit nodes.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

What's up with products not being as listed lately?

Day 00520: Monday, 2016 August 08

The mobile case that I ordered the other day was not as described on the product page. I knew that it likely wasn't waterproof, but it claimed to have a screen protector as part of the case. I double-checked the product page today to be sure. It says that the product is two pieces: a stylus and a protective case. It also says that it has a screen protector. While it doesn't directly say that the screen protector is built-in, it does say that there are only these two pieces; the screen protector must then either be a part of the case or a part of the stylus, but being a part of the stylus doesn't make any sense. Sure enough, the mentioned stylus is included, but the screen protector is not only a third piece, but a separate product within the shipping envelope. I tried to leave feedback warning people about the misleading product page, but eBay won't allow me to leave feedback without creating an account. I don't really feel like doing that at the moment, so I instead used the form to contact the seller. This form said that if the product wasn't as listed, my only solution was to request a refund, so that's what I did. The form said that if the seller doesn't respond by 2016-08-11, I can escalate this and have eBay step in to help. I will be doing that if the need arises. This isn't about the money, it's about having products listed as what they really are.

I also emailed NextStep Recycling to see if they've gotten any Wi-Fi cards in. Unfortunately, their email contact form didn't offer any form of confirmation, so I can't even be sure that it got through. I'll just have to hope for the best and perhaps try again later.

I tried to test my SIM card in my mother's old mobile, thinking that it might have a Wi-Fi hotspot function that could be used with my plan. It was a long shot, but no harm could be caused by trying. I found that the device is indeed not SIM card locked, as it connected to the Internet, downloaded a notification, and received SMS messages from my carrier. However, as my mother had forgotten the screen lock PIN, we weren't able to even attempt to set up the Wi-Fi hotspot with it.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.1 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

University of [REDACTED] seems like a decent place to study!

Day 00521: Tuesday, 2016 August 09

I just received a letter from University of [REDACTED] today telling me that in two days, new student orientation will begin. It will end at the end of the month, and the next day, the beginning of next month, will begin the first term. The email also provided login credentials, recommending that I test them out right away. The log in credentials work as expected, which is certainly good to know now before the term starts, and the site seems to function well as far as I can tell. I figured that I might as well glance around, so I read through the listed software requirements to make sure that there wasn't going to be any issues. It seems that the university recommends (though does not require) that students use Firefox. That's a free Web browser available on probably almost every platform, so no problem there. The only outright requirement is that one has an Internet connection and the ability to read and save PDF and DOC files. They don't seem to care what software you use to do so, and even outright *recommend* installing LibreOffice (or getting a Hotmail account, which apparently allows you to work with documents online) if one doesn't have Microsoft Office installed! These people are much more reasonable than my last school. My last school demanded that Microsoft Office be used, regardless of if it was even available for one's platform. They went so far as to demand a screenshot from every student showing the "genuine product key verified" page of Microsoft Office Word to be sure that you not only had it installed, but that you had gotten it through means that Microsoft deemed acceptable. I can see me doing much better here than there. University of [REDACTED] *did* link to the Adobe Reader page saying that PDF-reading software could be gotten there, but it wasn't outright said that this was the only PDF reader to use; it seemed more like an assumption that it was the only one that anyone would *think* to use.

Over the past while, I've been working slowly and surely to pry my mother out of the clutches of Verizon. Verizon is constantly doing screwy things to my mother regarding their account, and now, seeing as we don't have Wi-Fi at home, my mother's data usage has gone through the roof. My mother had no idea that they'd been using so much Wi-Fi in the past! The spike in data usage was in no way Verizon's fault, but the steep price of data *is*. I've been telling my mother about two unlimited data plans that I know of that are cheaper then their current highly-limited plan. I've been dropping the names "T-Mobile" and "AT&T", as these are two of the four real carriers in this country and my mother would recognize the names. However, my mother mentioned wanting to go in in person and get these plans in writing, so I had to explain that you can't get them through T-Mobile and AT&T directly; you've got to get them through "MetroPCS" and "Cricket". This throughly confused them, so I had to explain that these were only shell companies and that the real companies are operating under different names with different plans just to make make money from those that want to pay less while still being able to charge more from those that want the name brands. I explained that Sprint is doing the same thing under the names "Virgin Mobile" and "Boost Mobile", and to avoid making it seem like Verizon is the upfront one, I mentioned that Verizon probably has some alternate names under which they sell alternate plans as well. I don't remember what any such names are offhand, but I don't know why Verizon would be the only carrier not participating in such deceptive tactics. Mentioning Verizon was a mistake. My mother now wants to try to figure out what Verizon's alternate name/names is/are and take a look at the plans offered under that/those names instead. I was *so* close to costing Verizon a customer ...

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Basic computer concepts

Day 00523: Thursday, 2016 August 11

I've been routing my mother's Internet traffic on their desktop machine through Tor on my mobile. The fact is, if I didn't route this traffic through my mobile, my mother's machine wouldn't have any Internet connection at all, as we're currently living without home Internet service. If my connection is being used, I'm absolutely not going to expose my IP address for it. It's not my job to do that. Anyway, my mother decided to pay a visit to craigslist. The first problem here is that craigslist maliciously discriminates against Tor users, so they were sending nothing but HTTP 403 Forbidden response codes and error pages. The second issue is that my mother uses Internet Explorer. Internet Explorer has this fun little feature that causes it to avoid displaying error pages. Instead, it displays a "possible causes" message. Instead of allowing the user to hear directly from the server what the issue is, Internet Explorer wants to interject with mere *guesses*! In this case, Internet Explorer said that the most likely cause is that one must log in before viewing pages on that website. I swear, Internet Explorer is moronic. There was no value in explaining what I believe the cause of the problem was though, as it would be interpreted the wrong way. My mother would blame the proxy, but it's not the proxy's fault. The proxy isn't blocking the page. No, what my mother will likely always fail to grasp is that the problem is those that maliciously discriminate against proxies. In any case, as no real information on the issue was actually available, I didn't make such speculations out loud. Instead, I worked with the information provided. I said that clearly, craigslist was having issues at the moment, then convinced my mother to try a different website. I'm surprised that they were willing to try something else, given their usual attitude, but they indeed did take their business elsewhere.

Later that day, my mother wanted to go through their photographs and print out a couple hundred of them. They had me back the photographs up to their desktop machine earlier in the day, but then for some reason felt the need to upload them directly from the mobile to some Google service. Mother said that they were going to try to put the couple hundred that the wanted on a DVD, so I said that I could burn photographs that are on the computer, not on Google, to the DVD if they wanted help. They said that that would be great, but wanted to finish the Google upload that they were in the middle of first because if that was interrupted and the way I wanted to do it didn't work as expected (there's no reason that it wouldn't have), they'd have to restart the upload to do it that way. I left, and when they called me back over, they'd sorted the photographs that they wanted to keep *on Google* and expected me to save the files to the DVD! There was no indication of how to download the photographs back to the desktop machine in the Google interface, so I did the only thing that I could: I attempted to find each photograph in my mother's offline collection that matched what was displayed in Google. My mother came over to check and see how I was doing and what was taking so long, so I explained the situation. I had never said that I could burn images to a DVD from Google, only that I could do it from local files! I could of course save each thumbnail image, and burn those, but there would be a severe drop in image quality. My mother didn't seem to understand the difference between a file on a distant server that I don't have access to and a file on the local machine. They said that if I could only copy the ones from the local machine, I should just to that, so I explained that that is what I was doing; I was having to hunt down each photograph by hand from the local collection. So far I'd located three and failed to find two. Uploading files to Google then expecting to somehow burn them to a DVD had been a stupid plan, though I didn't say that part out loud. I think that because my mother could see all the thumbnails on the webpage, they thought that the actual photographs were within reach and could be saved directly to a DVD or anything else.

From there, my mother took over and started trying to make Google give them the photographs. I didn't think that it was necessarily possible, but the two of us worked together and covered each other's weaknesses. I couldn't fiddle with the account, as it wasn't my account and if I break anything, it'd be my fault. I couldn't do anything that would make permanent changes. My mother on the other hand couldn't tell the difference between the interface provided by the webpage and the menu of the Web browser itself. They didn't get that they two had different contexts and were limited in different ways in what they could do. For that matter, they couldn't distinguish these contexts from the context of local applications. First, they wanted to use the "save" option in the Web browser menu to save the album in photograph form (as opposed to webpage form) to the local machine. Then they wanted to use the "save" option in the Web interface to safe the album to the local machine (as opposed to save the changes made online to the serve). I was able to guide my mother around those pitfalls while they navigated the website looking for a solution that I thought might not even exist, until I spotted the "download" option which was what we clearly needed.

In retrospect, it seems rather obvious that Google would offer *some* way to download the photographs that one uploads, though they did make that option difficult to find and an "album" had to be created from the subset of photographs that my mother wanted first, while somehow the set that my mother had set up before was not considered to be an album. Mostly, I think that I didn't think that it was possible because I was still flabbergasted by the inefficiency of uploading files for sorting that you actually want to be stored locally.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Gathering GSM carrier pamphlets

Day 00524: Friday, 2016 August 12

I was supposed to ask eBay to step in yesterday and help with the the seller of my new mobile case, as they still haven't written back to me, but between forgetting for the first part of the day and being busy later in the day, I decided to give them an extra day to respond. I still hadn't gotten a response today though, so I asked eBay for help. eBay said that they'd get back to me within forty-eight hours, so I expected a two-day wait, but they got back to me within the day. They decided to settle the case in my favor and issue a full refund. They said to log into my PayPal account to receive the refund, but I didn't use a PayPal account to make the purchase. On PayPal's end, it had been an account-free transaction. I did receive a letter from PayPal, but the letter was written in Chinese or something for some reason. I couldn't read it! I've reached out to PayPal support to try to get a translation of it. I'm not sure why they decided to send the letter in Chinese though. My billing address is clearly in the United States, so the two most likely languages that I'd be able to read are English and Spanish.

While I remembered to deal with eBay support yesterday (just not right when I woke up) and decided to put that off for another day, I completely spaced it and forgot that my university orientation was supposed to begin yesterday as well. I logged into the school today and completed this week's orientation lesson up to the assigned readings. I'll complete the assigned readings tomorrow, then continue the next section of the orientation the next day.

My mother left today for a job interview and a social event. They're not yet sure when they'll be getting back. Since they were gone, Vanessa and I took the opportunity to walk around town gathering GSM carrier pamphlets. It might not be too late to get our mother off of Verizon and onto a GSM-based carrier, provided that I can prove that the GSM-based carriers have better deals. In particular, we needed the MetroPCS and Cricket plan pamphlets, but we grabbed any GSM pamphlet that we could find. I've sorted them into three groups too. The first group consists of the two pamphlets that we were aiming for. I think that these are the most appealing candidates. The second group consists of three almost-as-good plans, but each has a flaw of some sort. One plan is slightly cheaper, but is postpaid instead of prepaid. The other two are just as cheap as the main two plans, but have less high-speed data. The third and final group consists of every other GSM-based carriers' pamphlets that we could get. Depending on how much information my mother wants, I can easily provide concise or full information.

Vanessa and I also discussed the possibility of a new nickname for Vanessa. Our mother doesn't like that Vanesa prefers the name "Vanessa" over their legal name, so I've got to avoid using that name when they're around. However, if we can somehow get the nickname "Loch Ness monster" to stick, I can call them "Nessie". Our mother will think that it's a reference to the Loch Ness monster, but Vanessa and I will know that I mean it closer to "'Nessa", a shortened version of their preferred name. Getting the nickname "Loch Ness monster" to stick though is a bit of a long shot.

*Note*: The original journal entry for this date was lost due to carelessness. It was reconstructed on 2016-08-19 and may not contain all of the information that the original journal entry had.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

FreedomPop isn't what they look like at first.

Day 00525: Saturday, 2016 August 13

My mother wants a telephone number that reaches me but cannot stand the fact that my telephone number changes once or twice each year. With the way that I use mobile service, there's no avoiding a number change, and my mother doesn't find home telephone service to be acceptable, even if that did somehow get around the number change issue (which I doubt that it would, especially if we keep moving around and switching homes). Porting numbers is absolutely not an option and I'd rather not pay for a second line if I don't have to. I decided to try FreedomPop. They offer gratis service, though only in small quantities, and they seem to now be GSM-compatible (previously, they only offered CDMA-based service). I purchased a SIM card from them that was supposed to be compatible with both T-Mobile and AT&T devices, but after the payment was accepted, only *then* did they alert me to the fact that in order to place/receive calls/SMS messages, a proprietary application would need to be installed. Without that application, this company only provides data service, and the amount of data provided each month is too small to be used for anything. With the right guide, it might, though not likely, be possible to get calling routed through the SIP feature of the telephone application, but I don't see any way to get SMS service working, and SMS service is what my mother obsesses over most. I tried to get ahold of FreedomPop to cancel the service, but they didn't write back. Maybe I can reach them tomorrow.

I started working my way through the assigned reading of my school orientation today, but I didn't finish it as planned. It's not that there was a whole lot to read or that I didn't have the time though. I suppose I was just being lazy today. I could use cleaning up the porch as an excuse, but really, I had time to do both.

Speaking of cleaning up the porch, I've now trimmed away all of the blackberry vines and tree branches that covered the porch just off my mother's bedroom and made it unusable. Likewise, I've cut a path between that porch and the one behind the dining room so that I could carry things between the two. I've removed all items from my mother's porch aside from what I believe to be a pond filter so that I can power wash it tomorrow. The pond filter is far too heavy for me to lift. I guess I'll just have to wash around the filter until I can figure out how to wash under it. My job for tomorrow will be to complete the power washing aside from this spot under the filter.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

My old domain registrar is trying to steal my money and I sold out to Google Voice.

Day 00526: Sunday, 2016 August 14

It's too late to cancel the FreedomPop order now; they've shipped it. FreedomPop still hasn't responded to me though.

While power washing the porch, I decided that I should at least try to scoot the large, heavy pond filter to another section of the porch, power wash under it, then scoot it back. While attempting to do that, I found that water was being sloshed out of a hole on the side. Why was the filter full of water? No wonder it was so heavy! We've never actually used that filter as far as I know, so I'm guessing that the water inside is somehow rainwater. The lid on top should have kept the rain out though, so I'm not sure why the thing is full. After dumping it out, the filter became much easier to move. Furthermore, it doesn't appear to be an actual filter, but just the shell of one. We certainly wouldn't have intentionally filled it with water without an actual filter being present in there. I should have completely power washed the porch today, but I ended up arguing with my old domain registrar all day. I could have worked on washing the porch between messages to them, but I was far too stressed by them to get hardly anything done.

Because of the incident, I lost all of my passwords to every account that I had anywhere online. Knowing that I wouldn't be able to get back into any accounts that had automatic payments set up, I had Discover mark my card as lost and send me a new one. My intent was that anyone with my old credit card number wouldn't be able to continue charging me and they'd have to allow the services that they provided me to expire. However, that, as I learned today, did not go as planned. Apparently, credit cards have a feature that allows a merchant to set up reoccurring payments without holding onto the credit card information. Therefor, when the credit card information changes, it doesn't have any effect on the future charges. My old domain registrar has been charging me for domain renewals on three domain names that I can't even access! I noticed the latest charge, which occurred a couple of days ago, because I was checking for a refund from PayPal/eBay. I tried talking to my old domain registrar to try to get them to stop charging me (by turning off automatic renewals) and if possible, refund only the domain that they charged me for two days ago. I didn't even ask for a refund on the other two domains. However, they outright refuse to turn off automatic renewal unless I provide a notarized letter verifying my identity. This is insane. They refuse to accept state-issued photo ID because they think that it can be forged, but they somehow don't think that this notarized letter can be forged. I refuse to create further identifying documents though; United States citizens already have way too many identifying documents. They fail to grasp the fact that I have access to the credit card statement too. Even if the domain names are somehow not mine, the credit card *is*, and I am not okay with them continuing to charge it. I offered to send them my credit card statement to prove that the card is mine, and even said that maybe they should disable automatic renewals, but send an email to the email address that they have on file warning the domain holder that automatic renewals have been disabled and that they may re-enable them with a different credit card if they so choose. No dice. While the domain registrar is trying to screw me over, it's not the fault of the representative that I dealt with. Besides, it's hard to be angry with polite people. I made sure to let them know that I was aware that this was the fault of the company that they work for, not their own fault, and said that I hoped that I hadn't caused them too much frustration. Next, I headed on over to speak with Discover.

My only choice as I see it is to file a charge dispute through Discover. Even the representative from the domain name company admitted that I was well within my rights to do so. In a best-case scenario, this dispute with prevent further charges and might even result in a refund for one or more of the three charges over the past year. In a worst-case scenario, all that i have to do is cancel my Discover card. While I greatly hope that Discover does their job and revokes authorization for continued charges from the domain name company, the fact is, if the account is gone, no further charges can be made. My Discover card is the best credit card that I've ever had (though I admit I've only had two), so I'd hate to lose it, but it's also true that getting the card involved use of a telephone back before I started refusing to use a telephone number as a personal identifier. Simply put, I shouldn't even have a Discover card because obtaining a Discover card required telephone service. If I do end up having to lose my Discover card, in a way, it would only be the correction of a mistake, not the loss that it would feel like. It would feel like a loss though; I was able to get a card under my preferred name (as opposed to my legal name) through Discover, so without that card, online purchases (and anything that automatically renews) may never be the same. It sounds like the charge dispute will work though. I explained the situation to a Discover representative, and they said that they are going to give the domain company a full fifteen days before acting, but on 2016-08-30, they said that they will get back to me and initiate the dispute if still necessary. I let Hover know of Discover's decision in case it would make any difference, and am anxiously awaiting the thirtieth of the month.

I finished my university readings for the week and moved on to work on the discussion assignment. Much to my surprise and delight though, there wasn't a discussion assignment this week and it sounds like there won't be any at all during the orientation. Discussion assignments are bad enough when they're graded, but when you're not even going to get credit for them, it seems like even more of a waste of effort. Don't get me wrong, I'll put in the effort, but I never learn anything from the discussion assignments. Basically, the whole class just sits around reciting what we all already learned throughout the week. I'm not sure what anyone else is gaining from this or what we're expected to accomplish, but it just seems like lost time and unfruitful effort. Perhaps it actually helps certain people learn though.

This week's assignment was simply to fill out our university profiles, which are visible to the other students. Uploading a photograph of oneself was listed as a requirement of the assignment, but as the assignment isn't graded, I just skipped that part. There's no reason that anyone needs a photograph of me. I did complete all other listed requirements though. It seems that there will be a graded journal entry each week too, though not during orientation. I suppose that I'll probably quote those in this journal, as it's my real one, and there's no reason to have a fragmented journal setup. With the only asignment done, I'm done with the orientation for the week. School weeks at this university are measured from Thursday to Wednesday, so it'll be a few days before the next readings and assignment.

I finally got around to fixing the DNS-leaking issue in my mail client. My plan was to replace the client with one that didnt' leak, but that didn't end up happening. I went to the people of #tor for advice, asking what PGP-enabled mail clients that they knew of without DNS leakage. They said that the only one that they knew of was actually Thunderbird, but only with the TorBirdy extension installed. I don't even need to switch mail clients again! I went to the Thunderbird extension repository to find TorBirdy, but the description said that if one is running Debian, they should install it through Debian's package manager, so that's what I did. For some reason though, the preferences were all in Arabic! I asked in #Tor how to switch the language of the plugin to English or Esperanto, and they told me about a bug in that version of the software. Purging the Debian repository version and installing from the Thunderbird repository as originally planned fixed the problem.

My mother can't stand that my telephone number changes and claims that using the SMS gateways is too difficult. On my end, the email end, I could understand that complaint. To use the SMS gateways, I need to first figure out what carrier a number is even serviced by, then locate the appropriate gateway to use. It's a pain, but it's worth it to use an email address as my own handle instead of merely a ten-/eleven-digit number. However, on their end, the mobile end, all that they have to do is send to my email address. There's no lookups and no effort. It's just as easy as sending messages to a telephone number. However, with my mother's data usage going through the roof without Wi-Fi access around to keep it down, I was able to do something that I've wanted to do for a long time: disable that blasted iMessage service on their iPhone. The iPhone by default sends messages using up data instead of using standard SMS messaging. Furthermore, because of a bug in Verizon's service, Verizon iPhones using iMessage don't work very well with the SMS gateways. Anything going to of from a Verizon iPhone through the SMS gateway will come out on the other side as an attachment instead of an easy-to-read basic message. I suspect that turning off iMessage and turning on SMS messaging will fix that. However, I also disabled MMS messaging because it too uses the data connection. Without MMS messaging, the iPhone refuses to send to send messages to an email address, as it doesn't want to send them via SMS. If I'm being honest, Replicant has this same antifeature. A basic flip telephone can send to an email address using basic SMS, but somehow these more-capable mobile devices can't. I actually suspected that this might happen though, so I tried to contact my mother yesterday. My message of course got through, but they couldn't reply. Now, they have a legitimate excuse for not wanting to use the SMS gateway: they can only receive messages, not send them. With regular SMS messaging out of the question (as my mother complains about my ever-changing telephone number) and SMS gateway out of the question (because of the buggy software stack that demands that the data connection be used), I searched for an SMS forwarding service. I asked if anyone know of one on #Android, and they told me to use Google Voice. I dreaded that answer, but it was honestly the one that I expected. The problem with Google Voice is that it requires a Google account to use. The problem with Google accounts is of course that Google demands a telephone number, regardless of if you plan to make use of any of their telephone-related services. In this case though, I was trying to get Google to forward SMS to another number, so there was no point in trying to avoid handing over the number, or so I thought.

As it turns out, Google Voice is in many ways a better service than what I was looking for. I was able to set it up to not forward to a telephone number, but instead, forward to my new Google email inbox. I can even reply to the email and the reply will be sent to the sender of the initial SMS message! The main catch is simple though. While clearly no telephone number to forward to is needed in this setup, Google demands that a forwarding telephone number be supplied, though it can be disabled. If the forwarding number is deleted, the Google number is also deleted and it seems to be impossible to recover. No new forwarding number can be added if there is no Google number, but without a forwarding number, Google won't allow there to be a Google number. This telephone-free setup requires a blasted telephone number that has been verified by Google! Thankfully, my telephone number will be expiring in about two months, after which, Google won't have a telephone number that reaches me. Furthermore, whenever I have the chance, I'll add any telephone number that I can (as long as it's not my number or won't be my number for much longer) to the account to further dilute their information. Also, use of Google Voice is in desperation here, but now that I have the account, that doesn't mean that I can use it for anything else. Because the account had me verify a telephone number, regardless of the fact that that number won't reach me for much longer, I cannot use the account for any other Google service. This account must remain isolated in every possible way. As a further catch, the main benefit of Google Voice (being able to make it look like I'm sending from a telephone number instead of an email address) is it's second-to-main drawback as well (the main one being that a verified telephone number is needed to set up the account). If my messages appear to come from a telephone number, they don't appear to be coming from my email address. I should only use this account to contact people that I for some reason cannot reach via the SMS gateways, with the exception of my mother, whom I can reach but they cannot reach me.

It sounds like my mother will be coming home tomorrow.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Proprietary pedometers

Day 00527: Monday, 2016 August 15

For some reason, the power washer is failing today. The motor keeps shutting off and turning back on in quick succession. If I try to wash the porch with it, I'll probably end up burning out the motor. I should have finished cleaning the porch yesterday when the darn thing was working ...

I ended up going to a grocery store today, one of those stupid ones that charges you more if you don't carry a tracking card and allow them to chain your purchases together so that they can build a profile of you. My go-to solution for that is to pick up a new tracking card every time that I go in. That way, they don't charge me more, but as I only use each tracking card once, they aren't able to build any sort of profile on me. They allow one to use these cards unregistered, which I always do, but sometimes, they ask me to register them in-store. When that happens, I show them that their system won't allow me to register without a telephone number, so as I have no telephone number to give them, I cannot register. However, this time, the system actually *did* allow me to register! Mission accomplished. Maybe. I'd been dealing with the stupid registration form in Coos Bay, but the one that allowed me to register was in Springfield. It could be that they actually fixed their form to not demand a telephone number or it could be that these two stores are using different forms for registration. I'm really hoping for the former. I doubt that my complaints alone got them to fix it, but perhaps I wasn't the only one complaining.

My mother arrived home, but it doesn't sound like they think that their interview went well. That's disappointing.

I handed the two main mobile pamphlets to them and said that I also had more options if they didn't like those two, but that those two were the best options available in my opinion. They were happy to have the plans in writing as they had wanted, but it turns out that they are going to use them to try to haggle with Verizon! They're not interested at all in switching service providers any more, and think that Verizon can somehow be reasoned with if shown that there are much better deals available. I doubt that Verizon will budge much, if at all, so now I guess I'll wait for that plan to fail. There might still be hope of getting my mother to leave Verizon. If they don't, they'll continue paying through the nose for a restrictive mobile plan.

I found (and reported) a strange bug in Duck Duck Go. When you search for the term "user agent", Duck Duck Go displays the contents of your Web browser's HTTP User-Agent header. However, if your Web browser doesn't send a User-Agent header, Duck Duck Go instead displays a seemingly-random User-Agent string. Every time that you refresh the search page, a new User-Agent string is displayed, and they look like actual User-Agent strings used by different clients running on different operating systems. My best guess is that when a client requests the page and sends a User-Agent header, the contents of that header are copied into a persistent variable. However, when no User-Agent header is sent, the variable isn't erased; instead, nothing happens. Next, when one performs a search that triggers Duck Duck Go's User-Agent string display, it shows the contents of that variable. But why is the variable persistent? That part makes no sense to me. There's no reason to save the contents of the User-Agent header after the page has been sent to the client.

The Tor Project teeshit team finally got back to me after four months. By now though, my node is down, so they couldn't find it to verify it. I explained that I'm in the process of a move and have no Internet connection. I can't run a node without an Internet connection. FreedomPop also finally got back to me, but it's too late to cancel the order because the SIM card has already been sent.

I've been invited to a new IRC network, one that offers both TLS and an onion address! Umbrellix is still a small network, but it should be a nice place to hang out now that I'm not on Volatile.

My old domain registrar asked for feedback after having closed my issue yesterday. As they were refusing to stop charging my credit card for services that I can't access, I left them very poor feedback. What did they expect? A new representative got in touch with me today about the poor feedback and tried once more to get me to produce a notarized letter proving my identity because photo ID is somehow not good enough. I had been unable to access the Web page on which the discussion had supposedly been happening (I needed login credentials but lacked any), so I'd been replying via email, which posted to that page for me. The new representative today noticed that my emails had a signature mentioning my PGP key, so the representative tried to appeal to my clear appreciation of security, saying that the noterized letter was really needed to make sure that someone that didn't own the domains was. I relied in no uncertain terms that this "security" feature wasn't really all that secure, then proceeded to explain that it doesn't even matter if I own the domains, as I own the credit card. I haven't asked for access to the domains, I just want my card to stop getting charged. My response is below. I've redacted the names for privacy.

Hello, [REDACTED: current representative]!

I do appreciate security, but your "security" mechanism makes no sense. You (or rather, [REDACTED: other representative]) said that photo ID can be forged. However, it seems like a notary document would be easier to forge (as [REDACTED: other representative] said that any of a number of people could legally produce it) than state-issued photo ID. Furthermore, I have no intention of needlessly having more identity documents (such as this notary document) created. There already exist too many identity documents for everyone in the States. You want my photo ID? You got it. You want my birth certificate? You got it. You want my Social Security card? Well, I guess that that one's a bit sensitive, but you get the point.

Ignoring the refund for a moment, you have no reason to continue charging my card from this point on. I've let you know that I cannot access my account. I clearly am the one in charge of the card, even if I'm somehow not the one in charge of the domains, as I have pulled up the record of all three charges that you made to my card over the past year. I can even provide a copy of my credit card statement to prove that I'm actually the card holder if you like. I'm not asking that you give me access to the domains. I'm asking as the card holder, not the domain holder, that you simply stop charging my card. If you want, send a warning email to the email address that you have on file letting them know that auto-renew is disabled and that they can re-enable it with a different credit/debit card. This letter will hit an inbox that no one has access any more, but due diligence might demand that you make an effort to at least try.

So is it ICANN that is saying that photo ID won't work? If that's the case, it's either a new rule or Gandi.net is in breach of it. Either way, it doesn't really matter. ICANN is the same group that says that I can't own a domain under a gTLD just because I don't have telephone service, despite the fact that telephone service is in no way related to domain name ownership. Their rules often don't make sense; I see no reason for me to bend over backwards to meet their whims.

If it is truly ICANN's decision that a notarized document must be provided, then I understand that this is not in any way [REDACTED: domain registrar]'s fault and there is nothing that [REDACTED: domain registrar] can do. However, I hope that you understand that creating additional unnecessary identity documents is in no way acceptable in my opinion. If the only thing that I can do is have Discover revoke authorization for you to charge me further by following through with a charge dispute, then that is what I clearly have to do.

Thank you for your time,
[REDACTED: my legal name, present in the whois records]

My mother uses a strange pedometer to track their walking habits. They try to walk at least ten thousand steps each day, which is strange considering that they're against being a pedestrian. They do want to keep their health up though, and their family's poor health scares them. Vanessa, Cyrus (before Cyrus left for Gresham), and I tend to go out on our mother's walks with them. The pedometer that my mother uses doesn't have a screen though. You cannot tell how many steps you've taken without another device. The pedometer can sync up with either a mobile device or a Windows/OS X machine, but in all of these cases, it needs a proprietary application to do so and sens that data to the company over the Internet. Add that to the fact that the pedometer records not only footstep data but also heart rate throughout the day and sleeping habits and you have one creepy pedometer that I couldn't use even if I wanted to. Several times, my mother has asked if we've wanted some ourselves. Vanessa has shown some interest, but every time, I say that I do not want one. I don't give any reasons, as my mother would take it as an attack, but I always say "no". Once more, our mother asked if I was interested in having one, so I gave a strong "no". I thought nothing of the event until later, when our mother gave one to Vanessa. As it turns out, our mother had bought Vanessa and I each one, though I hadn't been made aware that the pedometers had already been boughten until just then. I'm not sure why my mother would have bought me one when I always tell them that I'm not interested. I even downloaded a pedometer that runs on my mobile alone on our last walk! My mother said that it wasn't too late if I decided I wanted one, so I explained that those things weren't compatible with my system. I left out the part about how creepy they are, and simply said that they are only Windows- and OS X-compatible. They said that they thought that I had a smartphone, as if the thing could sync with any smartphone, so I explained that it might be compatible with my stupid carrier-provided device, but there was no way that it would sync with my good device once that arrives in the mail. I'd been thinking that syncing would require the proprietary software that's only available with a Google account and the Google Play services software installed on the device, but when I thought about it later, I came to a better realization. Even if I used some service that bypasses the Google Play Store (and I have seen a few of those available), the pedometer syncs over bluetooth. Replicant isn't bluetooth-compatible. Vanessa seemed to be pretending to like theirs, though they didn't seem to actually like it. I asked about that once I got the chance, and it seems that Vanessa was very exited about the thing at first, but was beyond disappointed (going so far as to say that they now hated the pedometer) once they came to the realization that they weren't going to actually be able to see their step count. Vanessa's on Debian like I am and their mobile device is an actual telephone, not a mini tablet computer that people mistakingly refer to as a telephone (Vanessa hates touch screens). That device isn't going to run any sort of synchronization application, nor will it display the step count. If this thing ran using free software, surely someone would have modified it to work on Linux by now. This is one of the costs of proprietary software and why it needs to be avoided. As long as there is a demand for it, proprietary software will continue to thrive and continue to put up barriers to accessibility.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

A strange growth on the cat

Day 00528: Tuesday, 2016 August 16

The power washer continues to act up today. I'm not sure what the deal with it is.

My mother and I took a trip to the recycling center to try to find a Wi-Fi dongle for their $10 USD laptop that we picked up at a yard sale the other day. Vanessa asked me to look for a Windows/OS X laptop there to use only for syncing and reading their new pedometer, but we both knew that even the Linux machines there are more expensive than that, so I didn't find one. We did find a Wi-Fi dongle, but we weren't able to test it until we got home due to the short life span of the laptop's battery. It turned out not to function though. It's really odd too, as the paper insert that came with the Wi-Fi dongle specifically mentions functioning with Windows XP, which is running on that machine. Oh well, I suppose we'll just need to return the dongle then. While we were at the recycling center, I should have looked for replacement power cords for //newdawn.local., but I didn't think of that until after we'd left.

I managed to sneak a look at the receipt from my mother's recent pedometer purchases. They cost $60 USD each! That's a pretty expensive gift to buy someone that's you don't even know will want the thing! That doesn't take into account either the fact that I've actively expressed *disinterest* in it. Speaking of the pedometers, Vanessa started researching inexpensive mobile devices to try to find one to use with their new pedometer. I had told them that I know where to get them for $20 USD each, but maybe they wanted to find one even cheaper than that. In any case, our father wouldn't stop pestering Vanessa to figure out what they were doing online, and when Vanessa finally broke down and told them, they decided to dig through their stuff to locate one of their old mobile devices. Reportedly, Vanessa asked them several times to stop, but they wouldn't stop until they'd located the device and pressured Vanessa into taking it. Of course, our mother is offended that our father would be involved with the pedometer that our mother purchased. With both parents being control freaks about this, Vanessa's not seeing any way to win besides to simply not play. They're again considering returning the pedometer to avoid further strife.

It seems that my auto-pay credit from Cricket kicked in yesterday, so I'm now free to turn off auto-pay. Now that that's turned off, the countdown to the end of my mobile service through them can commence. The coming month has been payed for. After that month, if all goes as it did last time, Cricket will shut off my voice features (which I don't use) and my outgoing SMS feature (which I also don't use). Effectively, I'll be getting a gratis month of data usage, along with incoming SMS. I don't need SMS service, but hey, gratis data will be nice. After both months have passed, my service through them will come to an end and I will be free to switch to T-Mobile.

The Tor Project teeshirt team that contacted me yesterday wrote back with unexpected news. It sounds like regardless of the fact that my node is down, they want to send me a teeshirt once I have a stable address! At first, I thought that they were waiting until I had my Tor node back up (though it didn't sound like I need to get my two-month streak back). However, after thinking on it a while, I realized that they are probably waiting because I said that I'm in the middle of a move! They probably think that I don't have a postal address that I can keep for long enough for the shirt to arrive. It's true that I'm in the middle of a move and don't have even basic Internet access, but I do have a stable enough postal address to accept packages, I think. Then again, the school year is quickly approaching. Whether my mother has found a job or not, we need to get moved to somewhere quickly. Otherwise, Vanessa will need to change schools mid-year. In any case, I don't mind waiting for the shirt. I might even wait to let them know that I've moved until I have my two-month streak back.

My university program advisor also contacted me today to introduce themself. I should keep their email address on hand in case anything comes up.

Vanessa was playing with Frances and spotted a strange growth on Frances' toe. That can't be good. Our mother thinks that it's nothing to be worried about and seems to think that it might be just toe skin that's gotten a bit inflamed or something. Another possibility that they brought up, and one that seems more likely,is that it's a skin tag. If that's the case, it could be bad or it could be nothing. There's not much that we can do though, as we can't afford a veterinary bill right now.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.1 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

A bad day for my mother

Day 00529: Wednesday, 2016 August 17

After sending messages back and forth with PayPal, I finally got them to understand my situation. It seems that at first, they thought that I needed to file a dispute or something and that I had made the purchase using a PayPal account, but that for some reason, I kept giving them an email address not associated with that account. Once they understood that there was no PayPal account (I'd made a purchase as a guest), the dispute had already been filed and won (though the dispute was through eBay, not PayPal), and that PayPal had simply sent me an email in a language that I couldn't read, they were able to actually address the situation. They gave me a brief summery of the email, which basically just said that I'd recieve the refund in three to five business days. Perfect. I figured that it was a letter confirming the refund, but I needed to be sure. It's dangerous to assume.

On the way to the recycling center to return the USB Wi-Fi dongle that doesn't work with the $10 USD laptop, my mother told me about a job that they had applied for, but that their former coworker Alyssa had gotten instead. My mother seems to think that they're more qualified than Alyssa, though I haven't seen either of the two work, so I can't be sure. After a bit, my mother also realized that they'd somehow lost a day; they thought that today was Tuesday, but it's actually Wednesday, the day of a conference that they had wanted to attend. They accidentally missed it, which was no doubt frustrating.

We returned the Wi-Fi dongle to the recycling center, where the the salesperson told us that a computer that old might not be compatible with Wi-Fi hardware and that the operating system would not be compatible with modern software. I suspected that the software might be an issue, but until we could test it, I wasn't going to rule it out. It seems though that we're going to give up trying to make this laptop wireless. While we were there this time, I took the opportunity to look for charging cords for my laptop. The salesperson reminded me that the power cord must not only fit in the power jack, but also have the correct electrical output strength. I'd forgotten that laptop cords don't all have the same output. They didn't have any cords that were right for my laptop in stock, so I'll probably order a couple online once we are settled in a new home. My mother also wanted to know about the possibility of getting a Windows reinstall disk with the purchase of a Windows machine. The thing is, every time that they get a Windows machine from the recycling center, it eventually fails because it's Windows. The best way to fix the machine (aside from actually installing a working operating system on it) would be to completely reinstall Windows from scratch to reset to a default state. The recycling center won't supply such a disk though, so once a Windows machine from there has gotten borked, there's no fixing Windows. One must either buy a new copy, install a better operating system, or part with the machine.

Later that day, my mother was paining a table in the house, despite knowing that paining in the house is a bad idea. They managed to spill the paint in their bedroom, mostly on a plastic mat, but also a little on the carpet. I helped clean it up, but my mother really isn't having a good day today.

Vanessa is now again looking at the option of getting an inexpensive Android device to use with their proprietary pedometer instead of getting returning it to the store. I told them about the cheapest one that I know of, and we verified online that it is indeed compatible with the pedometer. I suppose that we'll go buy it when they have time to do so.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

I need to learn to keep backup copies of everything.

Day 00531: Friday, 2016 August 19

I've been storing my weblog entries on a USB drive due to the fact that I thought that //newdawn.local.'s power jack was failing. I figured that when the machine eventually kicked the bucket, which would probably be soon, I didn't want to be trapped away from my journal during the period of time between then and when I found a way to access the data on the still-working hard drive. Furthermore, because of the broken state of my journal (most of last month's entries are merely notes and need to be constructed into actual paragraphs; a few of this month's entries are like that too), I haven't been making Git commits and uploading what I have to the two online repositories that act as backup copies of this journal. Bad idea. I should have learned from the incident to keep backup copies at all times. I never formatted this particular USB drive, so it was still using the FAT file system, which is prone to breaking. It did break late last night, taking all of my journal entries that were stored there with it. Between what was still saved on my hard drive and what was still open in my text editor, I was able to salvage all but two entries: yesterday's and the one from 2016-08-12. Yesterday's was a short entry with not much to it, so it was easy to reconstruct, but the entry from 2016-08-12 was harder. I had to use clues from the days around it to even figure out what day that was, then attempt to remember everything that happened. I'm pretty sure that I've left some things out this time.

I tried to use testdisk copy the files from the damaged partition, but it couldn't even find them. Next, I tried to have testdisk repair the boot sector, hoping that that would restore access to the data, but that didn't work either. Instead, it seems to have completely deleted all the data on thee partition, so now even testdisk can't see anything there. The data is now lost for good. I swear, I need to get better about keeping backup copies.

I received a letter from someone saying that they want me to join their new startup, a development team creating mobile applications. I haven't managed to get my mobile application development environment working, but maybe I could get help with that. More importantly though, I refuse to develop proprietary code. I wrote back to tell them that I was interested, but only if access to the source code is available to everyone. I'm not sure if they'll write back, but if they do, we'll see if the new startup has any intention of working on free code. Someone else wrote asking me to sell them my domain. This is the second person that's asked for it! I explained that it isn't for sale, but that if they're looking for a short domain, perhaps my notes on ccTLDs would be of use.

University of [REDACTED] had now enrolled me in my first two courses. They've sent me my password in that same email though. This is the second time that they've done that. Clearly, University of [REDACTED] does not properly hash their passwords, and is instead storing them as cleartext. Add that to the fact that their website doesn't use TLS and you see that this isn't really the most secure place. Thankfully, I use a different password for each and every website, so a breach of security at the university won't compromise my everything, but the least that they could do is to stop sending my password out via unencrypted email where any eavesdroppers can read it.

My old domain registrar wrote back, again trying to claim that security is their top priority. Once again, I made it clear that continuing to charge a card that the card holder has made clear that they don't want charged is *not* security. To illustrate this, I brought up a scenario. What if I'd used someone else's credit card to set up automatic renewals without their permission? As the card holder and the domain holder are not the same person, the card holder would have no access to the account and be unable to prove that they are the domain holder, be case they wouldn't be. In this case, the card holder would have no remedy through the domain registrar, and the registrar would refuse to stop charging their card. In what way is that secure?

The compass on the GT-i9300 that was stolen from me didn't function correctly. I assumed that this was a limitation of Replicant. However, while I was reading about Replicant on the GT-i9100, I found compass calibration instructions for the latter! As it turns out, the GT-i9300 compass also needs to be calibrated. Now that I know that, I should have a working compass on my new GT-i9100.

My mother and I spent much of the day yard saling. Near the end, they started talking about getting a low-paying unspecialized job because schools don't seem to be hiring them. That's really got to be an insult to their pride. I'm not sure what I can do though, if anything.

Document modifications

On 2017-11-02, this journal page was modified in order to redact the name of the university and the link to their website.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Not a good day

Day 00532: Saturday, 2016 August 20

Google locked up my new Google account today. They won't allow me to log into it from any device, instead insisting that I go through recovery options. However, the only recovery option (despite the fact that I have a recovery email address set up) is to go through a form that submits to what I believe to be human reviewers. This form asked for the month and year that I created the account and the month and year that I started using Google's email service on that account, both which of course were this month of this year. They also asked for who my frequently-contacted people were (the only people that I'd contacted through the account were myself (for testing) and my mother) and the date of the last time that I'd successfully logged into the account, which was yesterday. They keep rejecting my attempts to recover the account though. I decided just to ignore the account and create a new one, as there wasn't anything else that I could do. However, Google wouldn't allow me to create the new account. As usual, Google demanded a telephone number for "verification" (read: Google demanded a telephone number to be nosy and over-controlling), so I provided the only number that I have. Google rejected this number, saying that it'd been used to "verify" too many accounts already. So I guess that two accounts is the limit, (The first account that I "verified" with that number, I later deleted that same day). Google is such a pain. Why did they lock up the account in the first place?

While trying to get Google to actually function, which I never managed to do,my Wi-Fi card gave out on me. That was frustrating. I needed to monitor my temporary inbox for letters from Google's team to get my account back, but I couldn't reach the Internet without my mobile. Rebooting the machine a few times didn't restore functionality to the Wi-Fi card, but with some help from someone on #Debian, I finally found a working solution. They said to turn off the machine and take the battery entirely out for a minute, then put it back in and try again. I never did figure out why my Wi-Fi card went out on me in the first place, but the power in the battery must have caused some internal state of the machine to not fully reset, causing the Wi-Fi card issues to be persistent.

FedEx sent me an alert that they planned to deliver my FreedomPop SIM card "tomorrow", on 2016-08-20. However, *today* is 2016-08-20! I'd say that the alert must have come from another time zone, but FedEx is a United States-based company and the alert happened too late in the day to have been correct in another time zone of this country. Later, I received another letter from them saying that the card had been delivered, so I went outside to check; it wasn't there. I went to the tracking page (FedEx, unlike the United States Postal Service, does *not* maliciously discriminate against Tor users), and found a surprise there. It said that the package had been delivered by the USPS! Why did the USPS deliver a FedEx shipment? Alternatively, how was a USPS shipment tracked on the FedEx website? I walked down to the mailbox to investigate. Sure enough, the SIM card had arrived, as did the GT-i9100, both a bit ahead of schedule.

With the SIM card in hand, I now looked into canceling my FreedomPop service. I tried to cancel the SIM card order as soon as I found out that their service wasn't as advertised, but FreedomPop support took so long to get to me that they'd already sent the card. First, I turned off the paid plan for the account, which FreedomPop puts you on (with a one-month gratis trial) by default. They probably hope that you'll forget to turn it off in time and end up having to pay for it; they don't give you the option to opt out of the trial when buying the SIM card or allow you to automatically revert to the gratis plan when the trial is over. It's a bit sneaky. Next, I tried to disable automatic top-ups, which cause FreedomPop to charge you as soon as you get near the end of your data limit, then use that money to pay for any extra data that you might or might not actually use. They should instead simply cut off your data when you hit your limit, but they'd rather do things the underhanded way. However, they charge a five-dollar fee for turning automatic account top-ups off! As the SIM card won't be in a device anyway, I just left it alone instead of paying the fee. I can't go over if the SIM card isn't powered on and connected to a radio. Next, I tried to cancel my plan and deactivate the SIM card. I couldn't find a way to directly do that though. I can deactivate the account itself, but if I do that, there's a $20 USD fee if I ever want to come back to FreedomPop. If FreedomPop cleans up their service, I might one day want to come back, so I decided not to deactivate the whole account. I found some information that hints that if I don't use the SIM card at all for about a month, they might deactivate the SIM card themselves though, so I guess that I'll just wait for that.

The first thing that I did with the GT-i9100 was check behind the battery for the model number. Would it be another GT-I727? No! The model number was clearly GT-i9100 as ordered, or at least it seemed that way at first. As the device was second hand, I wanted to be sure that it would actually connect to the towers, so I moved my SIM card to the device and booted it. Much to my confusion, the boot screen informed me that this wasn't a GT-i9100, but a GT-i9100G. THat is a GT-i9100G? Is it the same thing as a GT-i9100? Will it run the necessary operating system? As it turns out, no, no it is not and no it will not. THe GT-i9100G has a different chip set as the GT-i9100 and cannot run the same system images. It sounds like this version of the device might even be a bit easier to develop on in freedom than the GT-i9100, but as the Replicant team is under-staffed and under-funded, this hasn't happened yet. Why do these models have confusingly similar model numbers though? The fact that the product was incorrectly labeled as a GT-i9100 might have been an honest mistake even, caused by Samsung's similar model numbers and the incorrect model number being listed behind the battery. The similar model numbers don't end there though. It seems that the GT-i9100M might in fact have identical hardware as the GT-i9100, differeing only in default software. It's said that it can run system images designed for the GT-i9100 because of the identical hardware. Likewise, the GT-i9100P is supposed to be nearly identical to the GT-i9100, differing only in that it has *extra* hardware. Supposedly, this device can run system images meant for the GT-i9100 as well, though as these images aren't designed to use the extra hardware, that extra hardware becomes unusable, basically turning it into a regular GT-i9100. We also have the GT-i9100T. Wikipedia doesn't have much information on this device, staring that it's "functionally equivalent" to the GT-i9100. WHat does that mean? Does it mean that it can run the same system images? If not, that's hardly equivalent, but if so, it should be stated as such. Lastly, there might even be a GT-i9100I, though Wikipedia doesn't seem to have any information on it, assuming that it really exists. I've asked if the GT-i9100M can really run the Replicant system image just to be sure, but I'm not sure that I'll receive a response, as it's not one of the most popular mobile systems and people might not have tried it.

I reported the device to the seller as not being as listed, requesting a refund. They responded telling me that my request will be granted and to send it back. I won't be able to do that tonight, as the post office has already closed, or tomorrow, as they won't be open that day. I'll try to get it sent on Monday. Unlike the last seller, this one didn't supply postage, but did say that they'd refund any postage fees that I paid. Furthermore, they said that if the post office won't allow me to send the battery, to remove the battery and send back the device. I don't anticipate such a problem, but I suppose it's always good to walk in prepared.

I found a new mobile listed online as being a GT-i9100, though in the information about the device's condition, it says that it's really the GT-i9100M. Assuming that Wikipedia is correct, a device of either model should suffice, so I've ordered it. Unfortunately, with each try, the device gets more expensive. This time, it cost me $100 USD. Hopefully this time, I'll get what I actually paid for. If not, I might give up and choose an easier device to get ahold of. Last time, I had less idea of what I was doing and I still managed to get a *GT-i9300* on the first try. That might be a good device to try to reacquire, though it will also be more expensive and potentially less functional. The GT-i9100 is stated to be the most featureful Replicant device.

About two days overdue to get started, I dived into this week's University of [REDACTED] orientation material. Trying to make sure that my late start didn't cause any issues later in the week, I made sure to finish today as well. Besides, I needed something to do while I waited for Google to respond to my attempts to get back into my account. Unfortunately, it seems that the school library is hidden behind a CloudFlare CAPTCHA wall, so I suppose once school starts, that'll be something that I need to complain about, at least once per course, but probably not more than on a weekly basis. It would be nice if they got that fixed, though I need to make sure not to be annoying about it, so I'll probably lean closer to the once-per-course frequency. The school also mentioned a school-specific social network that they have for students, faculty, and former students, though they didn't at all mention where it was or how to find it. I wrote to my program advisor to ask about it, though admittedly, half the reason that I asked was just to make contact and show that I'm really here and did receive their initial email to me. The assignment for this week was to mark a few dates on whatever calendar system we each use. Unfortunately, my calendar is down when my server's down, so I won't be able to do that until we once more have a home Internet connection. I went to their list of dates to copy them into a plain text file for now, but their dates are displayed in the form of an image. Really? What is the point of that? I've saved the image for now. I'll type the dates into the calendar when can. In particular, the school wanted me to note the following dates:

The first day of the term
The Course Drop deadline
The Course Withdrawal deadline
The beginning and end dates for registration
When final exams begin
When final exams end

Looking for a Google-free solution to my SMS problem, I tried out a service called TextFree. They're Web-based, so they lack the email integration that Google Voice has, but if I could get their system to work, it'd be better than nothing. During registration, they asked me for an email address but not a telephone number, but then after verifying my email address, they blindsided me by demanding that I verify the account again by verify a telephone number, a Google account, or a Facebook account! That was not happening. I tried reloading the page though, and that seemed to work. My log in credentials work anyway, though I can't seem to actually send SMS messages. After submitting one, the page just sort of hangs and the message doesn't get through. Furthermore, every time that I log in, my SMS number changes. That won't at all work for conversing with my mother, which is the only thing that I need SMS messaging for. Maybe I can find another solution elsewhere.

Document modifications

On 2017-11-02, this journal page was modified in order to redact the name of the university and the link to their website.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Will my mother leave Verizon?

Day 00533: Sunday, 2016 August 21

I contacted my carrier to see if they had any ideas on how to resolve the Google account situation. They aren't affiliated with Google or anything,but they do sell a lot of Androids and they assume that Androids aren't usable without a Google account. With that in mind, they have many Goggle-using customers and had perhaps encountered this type of situation before. They said to telephone Google about the problem. I really hate telephone calls though, and besides, I don't have access to my mobile right now. My mother has it to use to connect their desktop computer to the Internet.

I spent the day yard saling with my mother. While we were out, my mother asked if there was a reason that the Internet connection through my mobile is proxied. So my mother does understand that a proxy is involved after all! I explained two valid reasons why the proxy is needed. First of all, my carrier doesn't allow me to tether. While this isn't technically tethering, the carrier wouldn't see it that way, so they'd shut me down if they knew what I was doing. The Tor proxy keeps all the traffic hidden beneath three layers of encryption, so the carrier can't tell the difference. Second, we're not doing this with a decent device any more. Simply put, this stupid carrier device refuses to use real tethering. Instead, we have to use port forwarding from the desktop to the mobile. That means that something on the mobile *must* accept traffic and redirect it to the Web. What does that? A proxy! The Orbot client has a built-in HTTP proxy, which helps with the fact that my mother's blasted Windows machine only seems to accept HTTP proxies, but even if it was SOCKS-compatible, SOCKS is still a type of proxy. I didn't explain the third reason for the proxy though, as my mother wouldn't understand. We need privacy. My mother has no right to expose my mobile's IP address just because they don't want to use a proxy. Furthermore, my mother has no right to expose that they're on my mobile to my carrier, regardless of if my carrier allowed tethering or not. To expose their presence on my mobile is to expose something about myself; I must be associated with the person generating that traffic. Furthermore, my mother's uploading resumes, giving their full legal name and address. There is no need for the carrier to have that information; all it serves to do is reduce my own privacy.

It sounds like my mother and I will be running errands tomorrow. I might not have time to walk the GT-i9100G to the post office. If this happens, I will need to wait until Tuesday. I've got to be present for these errands, as one of them involves talking to and trying to haggle with Verizon. There's no way that the haggling will actually work. Either Verizon will not budge or they'll make a tiny gesture that mother interprets as giving in but really isn't. I need to be present to attempt to tip the scales in favor of leaving Verizon. Besides Verizon being the most evil of the main four United States carriers and the fact that they're on a stupid CDMA network, Verizon has been ripping my mother off for years. I pay a smaller monthly bill and get unlimited data with, and I've been doing this and having this since I first signed up for mobile service. Why? Because I actually shopped around. (For the record, there was a period in which I cut my bill in half, but in doing so, had limited data and had to watch what I used, but when I'm paying full price, my bill is still only $30 or $35 USD.) Mother's highly-expensive, data-limited, overage-charging plan needs to be replaced.

My program advisor wrote back about the school's social network. It appears that I'll receive an invitation once my first term has started. The orientation really ought to mention that if it is going to mention the social network at all. Otherwise, the information is incomplete and leaves people wondering.

I asked to borrow Vanessa's telephone later for Google account verification, explaining exactly why I wanted it and what the drawbacks of allowing me to do so were. They agreed to let me use it, though there wasn't time to actually do that tonight.

Vanessa, our mother, and I went out on our nightly walk; Vanessa and our mother were engaged in a conversation. Vanessa said something that our mother disagreed with, and our mother just happened to tell Vanessa to stop talking right then because an idea was on the tip of their brain. Vanessa misheard part of the sentence, believing our mother to have said then stop taking in response to what Vanessa had said. Vanessa of course started to backtrack, taking back their opinion to appease our mother, so our mother freaked out at Vanessa. Our mother had wanted Vanessa to be quiet for a bit because there was a though on the tip of our mother's brain, and it had now been lost. Our mother claims that they would never tell us to stop talking just because they disagree with us, but they have done just that countless times in the past. They tend to do it only when angry, but Vanessa was perfectly justified in believing that this is what had been said. Our mother also swore at Vanessa for not following the actual instruction, despite the fact that they hadn't heard what was really said! And of course, our mother had to be their usual condescending self, telling Vanessa to pull their head out of their butt, despite this being just a simple case of mishearing what had been said.

It appeared that the Debian team is trying to integrate their websites with Tor better. They have added onion addresses for several of their websites. A list of Debian hidden services has also been made available, both on one of the hidden services and over the clearnet. The one catch to these hidden services though is that they use Tor's onion encryption *in place of* TLS. It's my understanding that onion encryption is no replacement for TLS and is actually a *weaker* form of encryption due to the fact that it was first implemented at a time when encryption technology wasn't as good, then never got updated. Speaking of Debian, it seems that Debian has Long Term Support versions! An article on new architecture support in Debian 7 LTS mentions that all Debian versions have a shelf life of at least five years because of the long-term support project. I thought that the main Debian release cycle was slow enough, but if you need a system to be super stable, the LTS versions are for you.

I am seriously running out of clean laundry here. It sucks not having a washing machine. We have a working dryer, but because the washing machine is leaking all over the place, we didn't even hook up the dryer. Tonight, I tried hand-washing three shirts and three pairs of socks in the bath tub. I've hung them up to dry, so I'll see how well those came out tomorrow.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

I could've gotten to the post office today ...

Day 00534: Monday, 2016 August 22

The shirts that I washed yesterday seem to have come out perfectly. The socks, not so much. They're stiff, showing that I didn't manage to get all the dirt out of them. At least they're better than before though. I can live with this.

The third "GT-i9100" has shipped today. It was listed as both the GT-i9100 and the GT-i9100M, so hopefully, the device is as listed and is one of these two models. If it isn't, I might just give up on getting a GT-i9100 and instead try to get ahold of another GT-i9300.

Yesterday, my mother was very clear that we'd be leaving in the morning to run errands. This was because they wanted to grab a Mexican desert that had sold out yesterday. The thought was that if we left early enough, the restaurant wouldn't have sold out yet today. However, we didn't leave early at all. In fact, I had enough time before we left to walk to the post office to drop off the GT-i9100G and walk back, without even hurrying, before we left. However, as I didn't know this, I didn't get the package dropped off at all. I couldn't ask my mother how long they were planning to wait before leaving either, as my mother would have started acting strange again about my running errands on foot and not accepting a dedicated ride from them. When we finally left to run errands, the restaurant had sold out of their desert again. There was a reason that we were supposed to leave early.

When we went to speak with Verizon, it went mostly as I had expected it to. They managed to convince my mother to stay with Verizon somehow, despite the fact that Verizon is over-charging my mother for a sub-par amount of data. The only other option that I saw happening was that my mother would leave Verizon. The option that my mother was seeking, a huge discount from Verizon, was never even a possibility. One thing good did come of the trip though. We brought up the fact that my mother's iPhone is guzzling data for things that don't require a data connection, such as voicemail retrieval and messaging, and the representative confirmed that this is just a thing that iPhones do. It cannot be used in any way to retrieve voicemail messages without using data, unlike Androids, which do it over the voice connection. That said, at the very least, I believe that there is a telephone number that you can call to retrieve voicemail messages from the iPhone; calling that number is what Android does behind the scenes when you hold down the digit one on the dialer. The representative also tried to show us how to disable iMessage so that regular SMS and MMS would be used, but I had already done that for my mother several days prior. The representative tried to claim that the iPhone is a data guzzler because it's a first-fate device while the androids are able to have the same functionalities without eating up the data allowance because they're second-rate devices, but that makes zero sense to me. I'm not sure if my mother was convinced, but hopefully, they instead saw the truth: it's the iPhones that are really second rate. In the iPhone world, there's no competition to drive up features and down prices. In the iPhone world, there's no freedom of choice, either between vendors or between places to get applications from. In the iPhone world, there's no sense of doing what makes the most sense for your use case; instead, data is consumed all the time in an effort to make things pretty instead of functional. While we were at the Verizon store, we also asked about my mother's locked iPhone. It won't accept the PIN and let us in, which is really strange. My mother insists that they know the old PIN and that it matches the PIN on their new device, but that doesn't seem to actually be the case. The Verizon representative informed us that they can't reset the device and that only an Apple store can do that.

My old domain name registrar wrote back admitting that their policies are a pain to deal with and saying that they hope to have better policies in place in the future. They have not actually admitted that they are in the wrong, but perhaps they actually are learning something from our little back and forth.

I spoke with Cricket about getting my device unlocked They want me to wait until the first of next month to get the unlock code. That's nine days past when their unlocking terms say that I need to wait. If I were staying with Cricket, I'd fight this, but as I'm leaving, I have the time to kill. I have a full month of paid service in which my device should be unlockable, but in which I also won't be needing to activate a new one.

Our mother has an interview in Beaverton tomorrow and wanted Vanessa and I to head up to Gresham with them tonight. What possible purpose for our coming up with them is there? This delays the sending back of the GT-i9100G by at least another couple days, which is frustrating. Furthermore, there's nothing in Gresham for Vanessa and I to get done. Because we're going to be in the area, we might be helping my pibling build their patio. We were going to bring the older of our two ladders to use as scaffolding, but my pibling declined that offer.

On the way to Vivian's apartment to stay the night, we picked up a pair of mobile devices, one for Vanessa and one for Vivian. Vivian doesn't want a smartphone, so I have no idea why my mother chose to give them one of those over a new flip telephone, but a new device was needed to set up service with a new carrier. To save some money, our mother wants to get Vivian moved to a TracFone account, but still wants to keep their own overpriced Verizon service. We couldn't find any of the specific device that we were looking for for Vanessa, a device that the website of the manufacturer of their proprietary pedometer said was compatible, so we bought two of the same smartphone and hoped that it would be compatible. The proprietary pedometer website doesn't neither confirms nor denies that this device is compatible, but Vanessa wants to wait until tomorrow to test it instead of figuring out where we stand on the situation tonight.

Document modifications

On 2018-01-16, my sister, Vivian, requested that I replace all instances of her legal name in my journal with the name "Vivian". She also asked that the name of the organisation she works for be redacted. This page was modified to fulfil that request.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

We need to get moved.

Day 00535: Tuesday, 2016 August 23

Vanessa dropped on me that the plan here in Gresham was to stay for two to three days .... our mother never told me that, and I didn't prepare for it. Out of paranoia, I did bring my old, unactivated, T-Mobile SIM card in case we end up staying for two months, but only because I couldn't stand not having an Internet connection for a prolonged period of time and because the SIM card was too tiny to be any hassle. If we were to be here for a while, I should have brought that package containing the GT-i9100G that I need to get sent back.

My mother went to their Beaverton, but they didn't get the job.

When they got back to the apartment, Vanessa, our mother, and I headed out to the house of Ken, our mother's sibling and Vanessa's and my pibling. It wasn't really a four-person job, so our mother sent Vanessa and me in and out of the heat. Vanessa and I got to work trying to set up Vanessa's new mobile to work with the proprietary pedometer. The application installed just fine, but the proprietary pedometer wouldn't sync with the device. Eventually, we gave up, and I went out to help with the work outside. There really wasn't much to do though. Ken needed to screw support boards up top for the roof, but being out of shape, couldn't lift them very well. My mother had been doing the lifting, as they aren't that heavy, so I wasn't really needed. I lifted a couple up too, but in all honesty, there was no reason for me to there.

My mother is upset about my eating habits again, this time that I don't eat nutritious meals. As I explained to them though, they get really weird when I cook, claiming that everything that I cook smells bad! I can't appease their overpowered schnoz and still get proper nutrition. They even complain about the scent of my salads, which are pretty much just bagged salad mix with Italian salad dressing! They never have any specific issue with the scent either, they just claim that it's unpleasant. Simply put, they get angry when I cook, so I don't cook; instead, I eat whatever I can that is both tolerable to me and has as little scent as possible for them. They claim that I'm just trying to blame them, but the fact is, I got pretty good nutrition when I was making mixed vegetable soup on a daily basis, and I felt a lot better than I do now. Now though, my mother decided to get a bit more specific. Instead of claiming that my cooking "smells bad", they're saying that it smells too much of garlic. I hardly ever use garlic when cooking, so I have no idea what they're talking about. I'll try eliminating whatever garlic does exist in my diet, and perhaps eliminate onion as well, and see if this fixes their problem. If not, I'll ask them to again state specifically what the problem is. My mother has agreed to try smelling the soup again next time I make it, so we might actually get somewhere on that front.

It's been several months and I still haven't activated that TracFone service card that I bought. Today, we used it to activate Vivian's new service on the device that Vanessa tried to use to sync the proprietary pedometer with the proprietary pedometer server. I was fearful that my service card would have expired by now, as I'd heard that the service cards stop working if you don't activate them soon enough. However, the card was still valid, and we (Unfortunately) ported Vivian's old telephone number from the Verizon account. Vivian didn't care if the number was ported or not, but our mother was strongly against Vivian getting a new telephone number. As for Vanessa, I talked Cyrus into giving Vanessa the device that I'd given them as we moved, the mobile that I'd planned to set up with that service card. That device was one of the models that the proprietary pedometer website said was compatible. We will return the unopened second new mobile device to the store when we get a chance.

It sounds like we need to get moved within the week so that Vanessa is able to start high school in our new location. We will be looking for a storage unit and housing tomorrow, then head back to Springfield.

Document modifications

On 2018-01-16, my sister, Vivian, requested that I replace all instances of her legal name in my journal with the name "Vivian". She also asked that the name of the organisation she works for be redacted. This page was modified to fulfil that request.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Telephone troubles all around

Day 00536: Wednesday, 2016 August 24

Alyssa's new carrier sent them a message saying that the service setup had been finished, but we found that it really hadn't. The new TracFone device wasn't able to make or receive calls while the old Verizon device was still able to. My mother telephoned the TracFone people, but when they asked for my mother's Verizon account information to use it to port the telephone number properly, my mother rejected that idea. I agreed that this was necessary, as Verizon isn't going to give up the telephone number to random people that ask for it. They instead need to be sure that the paying customer actually wants their telephone number ported away, but my mother wanted them to somehow authorize the port without that information. My mother also supposedly gave them that information through the Web last night, but they said that Verizon said that it was incorrect. Furthermore, my mother doesn't even seem to know what their account PIN is, so my guess is that they did in fact supply invalid information. Either my mother is going to have to supply this account information eventually, Alyssa is going to have to stay on my mother's Verizon plan, or Alyssa is going to switch telephone numbers. Porting the telephone number without proper authorization using information from the Verizon account doesn't sound like an actual possibility.

The other day, Verizon told us that only an Apple store could unlock their iPhone, so we headed to one on our way home. They took over an hour to even start helping us! This is the kind of customer support that Apple customers pay through the nose to get? Wow. Just wow. Not only that, but the representative that helped us seemed slightly incompetent. They weren't connecting simple dots, and I was the one having to bring up simple possibilities such as that the account email address might have changed (instead of there being a second Apple account). Add that to the fact that my mother couldn't even remember their account password, and it took a while to get us serviced and out of there. They managed to wipe the device, and now it should be usable, or at least as usable as before it locked up. Strangely, the device couldn't even function without a SIM card! If you take the SIM card out of an Android/Replicant device, you lose cell tower connectivity, but you keep all other functionality. However, we couldn't even get through the iPhone setup without a SIM card present in the device (the device complained, not the Apple representative), so the Apple representative gave us a gratis, unactivated, Verizon SIM card.

We were going to go hassle Verizon about the failed telephone number port out, but we needed to get back to Springfield on the double to check into a new storage unit before our reservation was dropped. As it turned out, the plan made yesterday wasn't to look for a storage unit, but rather to claim the unit that my mother was informed about yesterday. I'm never kept fully in the loop on these things. Cyrus (who came with us) wanted to joke around, and ended up bringing up the fact that my mobile device has an active telephone line now instead of just a data line. My mother was steamed! Somehow, despite the fact that I'd already told them that I was adding a voice/SMS line after my device was stolen, they still didn't know and blamed me for withholding this information. Why does it even matter though? They aren't going to like my telephone number because it's going to change, and I always try to get them to contact me via email instead of anything that involves telephone numbers. My having telephone service is completely irrelevant to anything, even though I *did* tell them about it. By the time we arrived home, the post office was already closed, so that errand will have to wait. Likewise, we're leaving early in the morning to move stuff to the storage unit, so I can't head to the post office right away. My guess is that I won't make it to the post office at all tomorrow.

Once home where they were able to connect to our father's Wi-Fi router, Vanessa successfully activated the proprietary pedometer and synchronized it with the proprietary pedometer server.

I borrowed Vanessa's telephone number as planned, and set up a new Google account to use when dealing with my mother. This should provide a permanent telephone number at which they can reach me without requiring that I actually keep the same telephone number when I switch providers. I used Vanessa's telephone number to get past the SMS verification, but then tried to use my own temporary telephone number as the number to forward to. That didn't work. Google disallowed the setup of a Google Voice telephone number if I used the same telephone number as the destination number that I did last time. I had to set Vanessa's telephone number as the forwarding number, then correct it to point to my telephone number instead. Google is such a stupid pain in the neck. At least I have the account set up and working now though. Hopefully, Google won't lock this account up as well. Last time, the account got locked up soon after I disabled "less secure application" access, but this time, that was disabled by default. I had to actively enable it to allow Icedove to retrieve mail from the account. Strangely, disabling call forwarding doesn't function as it should. Even if I disable all forwarding numbers, Google still stupidly forwards all calls to my telephone number but not Vanessa's telephone number. However, activating "do not disturb" mode seems to prevent call forwarding as I want it to. With that active, all calls are sent to voicemail. Voicemail messages are transcribed and sent to my email inbox, making this probably about as decent telephone-to-email functionality as currently exists. The one thing that would make it better would be not requiring active telephone service and a telephone number to set it up.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.1 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

The GT-i9100M runs Replicant!

Day 00537: Thursday, 2016 August 25

We began the day by moving furniture outside. We were going to rent a moving van, but my mother decided to take the minivan instead. We got three minivan loads of stuff into the storage unit, much of which was shelves and tables, so we can stack boxes on them later.

On one trip, on the way to the storage unit, my mother stopped at the post office. If they'd let me know, I could have brought the GT-i9100G with me so I could get that sent back as well, but I'm never kept in the loop on these things. Our goal in going there was to check on the security deposit refund check supposedly sent by the landlords, but the landlords said that the post office was refusing to deliver it. It turns out that the check had somehow been caught in the mail after all, though the postal worker was able to easily retrieve it for us. They claimed that the envelope had been all over the country, visiting all the wrong Springfields. They said that there are seven Springfields in the United States and that the machines can't read print. THe postal worker showed us at the bottom of the envelope where machines had added several barcodes on top of one another, each denoting a different Springfield that it'd visited. I found this hard to believe though, and it looked to me like the machines had put the same barcode in the same place several times, blurring it beyond machine recognition. If there was an issue with the address, I don't think that it was that there are too many Springfields (though I'm not denying that there are in fact too many Springfields). Just as a side note, there are actually far more than seven Springfields in the United States. While we were there, I asked about my ID card, which was supposed to arrive in the mail about two months ago. The postal worker blamed the DMV, saying that anyone that's moved in the past four months and updated their address on file with the DMV has been experiencing this issue.

The GT-i9100M arrived today; both the sticker behind the battery and the boot screen confirmed that it is indeed the GT-i9100M. Finally, someone sent me the device that I actually paid for. I had read somewhere that the GT-i9100M might not install the custom recovery correctly without first installing the Samsung-provided update, which alters not only the system but also the bootloader, so I tried to update the device. The device said that no update is available, so I assume that the update had already been installed by the previous owner; this is, after all, a second-hand device. I tested the back camera, which seemed to work well. After that, I proceeded with the installation. After installing the custom recovery, the device rebooted with large yellow warning triangle - hilarious! On the GT-i9300, only a tiny red exclamation point was added to the upper left corner of the screen. Strangely though, the text stating that the device is a GT-i9100M changed as well, now saying that the device is a regular GT-i9100. After installing Replicant as well, the device greeted me with the familiar Replicant loading image. Everything seems to work well. Fantastic! I tested the camera again too, which also seems to work well, making it more likely that my last Replican't camera was borked by water damage as I had thought and less likely that it was borked by a software update as I'd feared. I set my new PIN (which is now eleven digits long), turned on Privacy Guard, and started the device storage encryption process. While device encryption was starting, I put on the bad screen protector and bad case that I had ended up with due to an incorrect product-listing page. The screen protector has small bubbles underneath it that I can't seem to get rid of and the case needed hole poked in it to get a lanyard through to the device itself, as the GT-i9100M (and the GT-i9100) has a nice lanyard hole built in, but the case covers it up. I set up a stretchy, spiral cord from the lanyard to my belt loop, so that I can't walk off without my device in the future. Quite a while after, the device finished encrypting the internal storage, so I looked up the APN settings to use and set up the APN. I forgot that Replicant has F-Droid installed by default and started to download it to install ... A few seconds later, I remembered and canceled the download. I don't know why orWall quit working on the GT-i9300, but it works just fine on the GT-i9100M. orWall seems to have an updated interface though, so maybe some new update fixed the problem with orWall's init script, which previously, wasn't successfully initializing iptables. Furthermore, KeePassDroid now seems to default to a file name reflecting that a KDBX database is being used; KeePassDroid is now KDBX-compatible! It still accepts the older KDB database files, so I can still keep it in sync with my laptop, but when Debian 9 hits, I can safely update my database on both devices. GApps Browser doesn't render as well on Replicant though. Unfortunately, I need it for outgoing calls and SMS. I don't plan to use those with my Google Voice number often, but on the rare occasion that I do, it's going to be a bit of a pain. MTP on this device doesn't seem to work as well as on the GT-i9300, and even after formatting the SD card as an Ext4 card, the mobile was trying to store things on it using FAT. I ended up needing to transfer the files to the SD card from my laptop directly, instead of over MTP. After that, the device was able to read the music files, so I'm hoping that further writes to the card will be done using the actual file system of the card. It's worth noting that after Replicant had written to the card in FAT mode (rejecting any file with a name that FAT couldn't handle), my laptop couldn't even see the files, as they hadn't been written correctly. Lastly, this device is missing an indicator LED. It took me a while to figure out that it wasn't that the indicator led wasn't lighting up, but that it outright didn't exist. The thing that I'd been staring at was the front camera; when unlit, the indicator LED would have been invisible. No longer will I be able to glance at the device from across the room and see if it's done charging.

My mother has a job interview tomorrow in Estacada. Hopefully, they'll get the job. While they're out though, I'll have the opportunity to finally send back the GT-i9100G and speak to the DMV about my missing ID card.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

A long day of errands

Day 00538: Friday, 2016 August 26

This morning, my mother and I took two loads to the storage unit. My mother deliberately trying to avoid getting sweaty before their interview, we took very easy loads, consisting mostly of light-wight furniture and easy-to-stack bins. After that, my mother left for the interview, but it doesn't sound like the interview went well.

My first stop today was my credit union, as I needed cash to pay the post office when I asked them to return the GT-i9100G. On the way there, I saw that T-Mobile had an odd stand out with lip balm and some sort of noise makers, but no one was manning it. It seemed a bit strange, but I continued on my way. The credit union wouldn't allow me to withdraw any money though, as my temporary state-issued ID had expired! I'd be locked out of any credit union transactions that involved withdrawals, though they said that I could still deposit money as usual. My mother found a bond issued under my name the other day, so I tried to deposit that into my account, as I couldn't exactly spend it without depositing it anyway. As it turns out though, credit unions can't redeem bonds; only banks can. Lastly, I asked the credit union to activate the credit card that they sent me a while back. However, the representative told me that they could only be activated via telephone. When I explained that I don't have telephone service, they told me that there was nothing that they could do about it. After leaving, I realized that I should have asked them to cancel the card because I can't use it, but it didn't matter too much. I would need to return to the credit union soon anyway, even if I didn't make it back in time to make any transactions today.

Still needing money to pay the post office, I took a detour and headed home to borrow some from Vanessa, which I paid back later in the day. At the post office, things went mostly smoothly. I ended up needing to fill out customs paperwork, then the postal worker's computer wouldn't cooperate with them, but everything ended up sorted out soon enough. Once done, I asked for directions to the Department of Motor Vehicles, then headed out on the next leg of today's journey.

The trip to the DMV was a bit long, but there was nothing that I could do about it. I had to check on my semi-permanent ID card and get a new temporary one so that I could get back into my credit union account. Yesterday, the postal worker was blaming the DMV for my missing ID card, but today, the DMV representative blamed the post office. In fact, the ID card had been returned to the DMV by the post office, though this was no doubt because the DMV told the post office not to forward mail from them. What do you do when two government agencies are blaming each other for a problem? In any case, they said that they'd resend the ID card and that it'd take about seven to ten business days to reach me. Of course, I'm not even entirely sure that it has a better chance of reaching me this time than last time, but I'll wait and see how this pans out. They issued me a new temporary ID card, and I was on my way.

My walk back to the credit union was the longest leg of my trip today. I ended up getting lost due to the fact that sreets didn't go through where they should have and curved in unhelpful directions. At one point, I ran across a street sign pole that had become twisted about eighty degrees somehow. As a result, I thought that I was moving from Industrial Street to Thirty-Fifth Street, but I was actually doing the reverse. I finally made it back to a familiar area, where I saw that Cricket had a stand set up like T-Mobile, and I was going to be passing by the T-Mobile stand again, so I decided to stop and see what was going on.

The Cricket stand had more interesting trinkets than the T-Mobile stand. While I much prefer T-Mobile, I only grabed Cricket items. These items included a thin, plastic ZTE cup, a thin Cricket backpack, a Cricket lanyard, and a Cricket key chain/bottle opener. Inside the store, the representative told me that the stand outside was to celebrate the location's grand opening; that didn't make any sense to me though. This Cricket location has been open for at least a few months. They're holding a drawing tomorrow for a new Cricket device, so I entered that as well. There's no way that I'll win, but it doesn't hurt to enter. THat said, if I *do* somehow win the drawing, it'll mean that I'm stuck on Cricket service for at least another six months so that I can get the device unlocked. I'm only on Cricket now because I was in Coos Bay, where T-Mobile service isn't available.

Back at the T-Mobile stand, I inquired as to what their stand was about. They claimed that it was simply just about customer appreciation and wasn't really about anything else. As much as I feel that T-Mobile is the least underhanded of the four major United States mobile carriers, I had a strong suspicion that customer appreciation isn't what this stand was about at all. More likely, T-Mobile knew that Cricket would have such a stand at some point and had prepared in an attempt to avoid being shown up. Ironically, with T-Mobile's trinket offerings being so dismal, I think that they failed on that front. Luckily for them, I'm not a fan of T-Mobile because of their trinkets, but because of their GSM service, prices that are lower than other GSM carriers, and the fact that they at least partially are trying to avoid screwing customers over as badly as other carriers. I'm practically counting the days until my Cricket service expires and I can switch to T-Mobile service.

Back at the credit union just before closing time, I was able to complete my withdrawal using the newly-issued temporary ID card. I almost tried to redeem the bond again before remembering that the credit union legitimately couldn't deal with bonds. Bracing myself so I wouldn't back down, I asked the new teller that I was speaking to this time to activate my credit card issued by the credit union. Once more, they said that it needed to be activated via telephone. I explained again that I don't have telephone service, so they went and checked with their card-activation team to be sure that it was only the debit cards that could be activated in-branch. The card team confirmed, so with no other choice (using a telephone is an option reserved for only the most desperate of situations), I explained that in that case, I needed to cancel the card. THat got their attention! I legitimately thought that my only option was to cancel the card, but when presented with that option, the teller changed their tune and found another way! They spoke with a representative in the back and they were able to help me activate the card via their own company telephone. Was that really so hard? When activating the debit cards in-branch, they use this same solution of having one use the in-branch telephones. The representative in the back used the telephone in the back on my behalf, but honestly, I'd have been fine using any telephone provided for this task myself even, so long as they provided the telephone and the telephone service. It's unreasonable to expect everyone to have telephone service, and it should not be a requirement for any service-, support-, or account-related reason.

My mother had merchandise that they had wanted me to return to a couple stores as well, but I knew before even trying that that would be an impossibility. My mother hates using cash, much preferring to use their credit and debit cards. Returning merchandise when a credit/debit card was used for the initial purchase requires re-swiping the card. Just to say that I'd tried, Vanessa and I headed to the closer store that I needed to return things to, but as expected, we couldn't act without the card present. I didn't even bother going to the distant store though, as after running my own errands, I was exhausted. If the errand would have been a success, I would have happily run the errand despite my lack of energy, but when I knew that the errand would end in failure, what would even be the point?

I noticed today that I don't seem to be as attached to my GT-i9100M as I was my GT-i9300. If I recall, I latched onto the GT-i9300 quite quickly, even before touching the device. Once I had it in hand, I thought that my mother was going to try to get me to return it, as they were throwing a fit about my having ordered it without talking to them about it first (despite having talked to them directly about it right before ordering it and having been dropping hint after hint about it for at least a couple weeks prior). I carried the thing around all day without service, not yet flashing it in case it did need to go back. Once I flashed it to run Replicant, it only got better, as I could actually trust the thing with my information and not fear that it'd do everything that it could to steal my privacy. Somehow though, despite having more information about how to set Replicant up the way that I like it, this device just isn't the same. It's kind of sad, seeing as this device is in better shape than my GT-i9300 was near the end. The GT-i9300's camera was blurry and the SD card slot was failing. On the other hand, I've noticed no damage-related issues with the new (used) GT-i9100M. Why is this device not an improvement to me?

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

A house-hunting trip that involved no house-hunting

Day 00539: Saturday, 2016 August 27

Last night, //newdawn.local. was behaving a bit strangely, saying that it was fully charges and keeping it's charge, though the color of the battery indicator hinted that the laptop was instead discharging. Stupidly, I wrote it off and went to bed, probably partially because I was exhausted. When I awoke this morning though, I found that my laptop had completely discharged and shut off. Lovely. It's difficult getting the power cords to work at all, and when they do work, it's often only when in contorted positions. I managed to partially repair my scary, buzzing cord though. Now, it works in almost any reasonable position. What a relief! I was starting to again fear that the problem wasn't the laptop cords, but the power jack of the computer. There has been one regression in the cord's state though. Now, instead of buzzing only when charging (as opposed to when simply maintaining a full charge), the cord buzzes nonstop as long as it is plugged both into the laptop and into the wall. Seriously, as soon as I have a stable address, I need to get a pair of laptop cords (one to use and one as a spare) ordered online. This one's just scary!

The stretchy, spiral cord that I've been using to attach my mobile to my belt loop is a bit *too* long or stretchy. If I were to drop my mobile, it'd be allowed to hit the ground, and with the current case being as poor quality as it is, it might not stop the device from cracking. I decided to swap out that spiral cord for the Cricket lanyard that I picked up yesterday. Bad idea. That lanyard's metal components have a large protrusion on either side and one of them mangled the device's screen protector. I knew that that type of screen protector wasn't to be trusted ... I'll see if I can find a better lanyard when I get the chance, but I'll also need to get a better case for the device (or at the very least, replace the mangled screen protector).

Cyrus, Vanessa, our mother, and I headed to Salem, supposedly to look for a home. However, things didn't exactly go that way.

First, we went to Aumsville's corn festival. There, we were given gratis, cooked cobs of corn. Cyrus and I specifically asked for ours without butter, but anyone that didn't specifically ask for the butter to be left off ended up with buttered corn. Our mother found a dime-tossing game, which they played along with Cyrus and Vanessa. Sadly, there were a couple fish in vases among the dishes, and though they were covered so that dimes didn't land in their water, they darted every time that a dime hit something near them. They must have been scared out of their minds! Our mother was surprised that I didn't want to play, but either way, I'd lose that game. If you fail to land your dime in a dish, you've lost the dime for nothing. If you successfully land the dime in a dish, you still lose the dime, but you also get that dish. I could have aimed at dishes that were far from the fish, but it doesn't nullify one simple fact: I don't need more junk to bring with in the move or try to get rid of. Apparently though, my mother finds this game to be quite fun. They didn't even want the dishes, and after they were done tossing away their dimes, they even *gave most of the dishes back to the people running the game*. I'm not sure what the people running the game thought of that! Next, w stopped at a chiropractor's booth. They used some sort of electronic device to quantify how bad my mother's and my necks and backs are, then recommended that we see a chiropractor a bit closer to home than them. Probably the most important booth that we stopped at an energy efficiency booth, where much to my surprise, my mother bought three six-packs of LED light bulbs for ten dollars each! Usually, my mother is a bit strange about energy-efficient lighting and kind of stays away from it. Before heading out, we picked up two ten-packs of corn ears for a dollar each. That's some cheap corn!

When we stopped for lunch, Vanessa pulled out their laptop, which apparently our mother had asked them to bring, and our mother used the restaurant's Wi-Fi access point to browse craigslist. It seems like the main point of our trip to Salem was to evade craigslist's noxious Tor ban! We could have done that a lot closer to home, say, at the Springfield City Hall Public Library? Not only that, but my mother's insistence to continue using craigslist is a bit worrisome, and my mother continues to blame proxies for the issues, not those that maliciously discriminate against proxies. As it turned out though, my mother wasn't able to browse some of the listings because the the restaurant's access point censored certain websites and these listings were not on the main website. As I told my mother, a proxy would have allowed us to evade such censorship. Proxies are not the enemy, those that maliciously block proxies are.

In Salem, our mother pretty much just drove us around the town showing us the two main commercial hubs of the town; there was no actual house hunting involved. It appears that our mother wants to live near either of these two areas, as each contains a Winco, my mother's favorite grocery store. If we do end up living near one of these places, the fact that they're comercial hubs means that I'll also have many places to apply for work that are within walking distance. There's even a T-Mobile store near at least one of them, where I can pay my monthly bill in person. If we live near one of these hubs, Salem should be a decent place to live as a pedestrian/cyclist, I think.

The GT-i9100M's battery life sucks. It did not survive the trip, and I had to shut the mobile off near the end to keep it from completely draining the battery. I still miss my GT-i9300, which had better battery life.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

The end of the orientation

Day 00541: Monday, 2016 August 29

Current countdowns:

22 unfinished weblog entries in July
21 days until mobile voice/SMS service with my current carrier ends
51 days until mobile data service with my current carrier ends
2 days until school starts
6-9 business days (8-13 days) until my ID card is supposed to arrive

It appears that the landlords charged us for nine days extra rent out of the security deposit, which adds up to a lost $450 USD. My mother wrote to them to get that back, as we were only in there *one* extra day. We left early in the morning on 2016-07-02. We did leave some dishes in one cupboard until 2016-07-09, but we were unaware of them and they hadn't been in the landlords' way. They hadn't even noticed them until the ninth. As soon as the landlords notified us about the dishes that we left behind, we drove from Gresham to pick them up that same day! If the landlords don't respond, my mother plans to threaten to take them to court as well as hint that they'll turn them into the IRS. We don't think that the IRS knows about their rental income, as it was written into our rental agreement that we couldn't report ourselves as renters when filing our taxes. That's a bit shady, and no doubt was put into the rental agreement in an effort to evade taxes on the rental income. My mother says that they have no job, so they have plenty of time to go to court if it comes to it. If need be, my mother isn't afraid to fight for that $450 USD.

I really should have done it earlier in the week, but today, I finally completed the final week's orientation readings at University of [REDACTED]. This week's readings just covered some basic stuff that should be known, but needed to be restated in case people had missed it. Basically, all deadlines are hard deadlines, plagiarism is bad, complete your assignments early for best results, and stuff like that. I also finally got around to uploading a "photograph of me", which was the final thing asked of me on the first week, though it's actually the Debian logo. I'm really glad that I decided to upload something, as I got to see how their image uploader works. When uploading a file, the website asks who the author of the file is and asks what license it's under! All six of the mainstream Creative Commons licenses are options, as well as "all rights reserved" and "public domain". It would certainly be sweet if they enforced that a free license be used, but the fact that they even *allow* two different free licenses (as well as public domain, which is also free) to be used is awesome! I think that I'm going to do very well in this type of learning environment. The assignment for the week was to make a list of three things that we're exited about in attending the university and a list of three things that we are most worried about. There's no place to turn these lists in though, so I've just written them below:

Things that excite me about attending school at University of [REDACTED]:

I am finally starting to learn about computers in a more directed way again. For a while now, I've pretty much just been learning whatever random computer skills are needed for the tasks that I happen to need to accomplish at the moment.
University of [REDACTED] seems to understand that different people use different software, and actively recommends that people without Microsoft Office install LibreOffice. Unlike my last school, it sounds like University of [REDACTED] isn't noxiously stubborn about making people use the software that they prefer, and instead allows people to use whatever software can accomplish the task and works for the user.
The university even seems to understand the importance of Creative Commons licensing, though they also seem to support the proprietary Creative Commons license variants.

Things that worry me about attending school at University of [REDACTED]:

If University of [REDACTED]'s courses are set up as they should be, technology shouldn't be a problem. However, I'm worried that University of [REDACTED] might require proprietary software be used in some courses. If that does happen, I'm not sure how I can hope to complete such courses.
I might not have enough time to study, seeing as I'll need to hunt for a job and help the family move, among other responsibilities.
I might not have a stable and usable Internet connection for long.

I managed to get connections through ADB-forwarded ports to connect through Tor without disabling orWall now. It seems that ports forwarded through ADB are considered by orWall (and perhaps considered by the system) to be run by "Linux Shell", not "Android Debug Bridge (ADB)". By giving "Linux Shell" permission to get through orWall instead of giving permission to "Android Debug Bridge (ADB)", the connection can be made to work. That said, I still can't get regular tethering to go through Orbot yet. Instead, orWall just allows tethered traffic to bypass the proxy entirely, whether I want it to or not. It seems though that this is a known bug, and not an easy one to fix. At least with ADB-forwarded traffic being routed through Tor, I have a working network solution for the time being, though it is a bit unnerving giving my mother's Windows-based machine privileges to run arbitrary commands on my device.

Speaking of getting the connection working on my mother's computer, I've not got it set up in such a way that it's so easy to start, even my mother can initiate the port forwarding. I had to compromise the security a bit on my end; my mobile now automatically recognizes my mother's machine and allows ADB access without unlocking the screen on the mobile, or in fact, interacting with the mobile in any way aside from physically connecting it to the desktop machine with a USB cable. On my mother's end, I wrote my first-ever Windows batch file: a short script consisting of only one command. This is the command used to initiate the port forwarding. My mother's system proxy has already been set to use this port on //localhost., as when my mobile's unplugged, no other Internet connection is available to us at the moment. Strangely, I found that if the batch script is saved as any sort of Unicode, the first line of the file will be incorrectly interpreted, as the byte order mark added by Windows when saving in these formats will be interpreted as part of the command name. Pinning the batch script to the panel (or the task bar, as they call it in Windows speak) was more difficult than I thought as well. I thought that all that I had to do was write the batch script and drag it to the panel, but that didn't work at all. It turns out that I needed to create a shortcut to the script, modify the shortcut's target to point to the command line interpreter, and pass the script's path as a second argument. The first argument must be "/C". Because of how that had to happen, I'm fairly certain that the batch script wasn't needed at all. If I'd changed the shortcut to instead run the ADB command directly, it might have been more efficient. That said, I don't care enough to fix it. It doesn't make that much difference. Besides, Windows has never been about doing things the efficient way. Windows is slow and clunky; it probably will be until the day comes when it is finally discontinued. In any case, now all my mother has to do after connecting the device to the desktop machine is click a single icon on the panel. I might be able to automate this further by having the computer automatically run the command when the device is connected, but I'm currently unsure how to do that.

Document modifications

On 2017-11-02, this journal page was modified in order to redact the name of the university and the link to their website.

Further comment on "Unlike my last school, it sounds like University of [REDACTED] isn't noxiously stubborn about making people use the software that they prefer, and instead allows people to use whatever software can accomplish the task and works for the user.": Ha! Tell that to students taking CS 2301! Two specific applications are required for no good reason, leaving non-Windows users high and dry. The tasks required can be accomplished using other software, aside from the "use {insert specific application here} to do X" part. X can be done without the required software, X just can't be done *with the required software* without the required software.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Worrying about my new school

Day 00542: Tuesday, 2016 August 30

Current countdowns:

20 unfinished weblog entries in July
20 days until mobile voice/SMS service with my current carrier ends
50 days until mobile data service with my current carrier ends
1 day until school starts
5-8 business days (7-12 days) until my ID card is supposed to arrive

I awoke from a horrid nightmare this morning. I was back in school (online) and I was given the assignment to draw a circle in Microsoft Office. For some strange reason, the instructions said that only the latest version of Microsoft Office would be up to this task. Not only would LibreOffice not do the trick, old versions of Microsoft Office that run on Wine wouldn't work. My only choices were to fail the assignment or install both Microsoft Windows and Microsoft Office. Before I woke up though, it got a bit better. I realized that I was somehow reading an assignment from my old school. University of [REDACTED] had not assigned this task, and it would do me zero good to attempt to complete it.

I've been reluctantly leaving my mobile connected to my mother's computer overnight. Overcharging is bad for the battery's lifespan, but my mother gets up at strange hours (not intentionally), and sometimes spends that time doing things on the Web, such as applying for jobs. It seems that my mother got up at 03:30 this morning, but couldn't get onto the Internet. I checked it out this morning, and somehow, my mobile device had been shut off! My mother claims not to have touched the device in any way since we set up the connection yesterday, so that left one other option: the device outright crashed. Or at least, that's what I thought at first. My GT-i9300 never did that. I mean, it did crash sometimes, but it would always reboot after doing so. It wouldn't have brought back up the connection, as my mother would have needed to re-click the icon on their panel to tell their desktop machine to reestablish the port forwarding, but it would have made it possible to instruct my mother as to what to do next time that this occurs. If the device had crashed, there would be only one thing that I could do do: give my mother the decryption password of the device so that they can restart it. There is no way that that is happening though. Luckily, later in the day, I found the most likely real cause of the issue: the device had run out of power! When the screen is left on, the GT-i9100M consumes power faster than it can pull more power from the computer that it's plugged into. The GT-i9300 never had this issue, and charged much faster than the screen being on drained. When the GT-i9100M's battery was exhausted, the device shut off and continued charging.

I tried to set up a new auto-play action for my mother's Windows machine so that whenever my mobile is plugged in, the Windows machine automatically runs the ADB command needed to set up port forwarding through the device. No dice. It seems that by default, Windows does not allow one to add arbitrary commands to the auto-play options. I read that there are software solutions for this problem, but I don't want to take the time to try to set that up while my mother is home and might need their computer at any time. I might try to set that up while they are away.

I got ahold of my mother's mobile device and updated my contact information in it. I had to delete *seven* outdated entries holding old versions of my information. It's no wonder that my mother gets so frustrated when my telephone number changes. They can't keep their contact list organized! Instead of updating the old contact entry each time, my mother has been adding a new one whenever new information is presented. This should not be confused with adding a new telephone number to the old entry while leaving the old one in place. No, rather, there were seven full entries, each listed as separate people, but all sharing my name. I'm not even sure if it matters if my contact information changes now, as long as I'm the one to update it on their device, not them. Their inability to use computers effectively always takes my by surprise.

My mother and I took two loads over to the storage unit today after Vanessa and Cyrus helped us load them into the van.

Discover has cancelled my automatic bill payments. They claim that my credit union account no longer exists. I'm going to need to talk to First Tech about this. They still have some of my money! I was in-branch updating my home address too not to long ago. They had better not have cancelled my account.

Document modifications

On 2017-11-02, this journal page was modified in order to redact the name of the university and the link to their website.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.1 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

School starts tomorrow!

Day 00543: Wednesday, 2016 August 31

Current countdowns:

20 unfinished weblog entries in July
19 days until mobile voice/SMS service with my current carrier ends
49 days until mobile data service with my current carrier ends
0 day until school starts
4-7 business days (6-11 days) until my ID card is supposed to arrive
29 days until the payment dispute with my old domain registrar is resolved

I logged into my Discover account to make sure of what financial account that they actually thought no longer existed. I thought that I had told Discover to take money from First Tech Federal Credit Union, but that wasn't the case. Instead, I'd told them to take money from Banner Bank. They were completely correct yesterday when they said that the account no longer exists! Why did it take them this long to notice though? Where has my bill been being paid from? I told Discover to take this month's bill payment from Oregon Community Credit Union, then tried to set up automatic payments again. My credit card bill is the one and only thing that I like to have on automatic payments. However, it seems that because I attempted to pay my bill before setting up automatic payments, setting up automatic payments would have caused me to be double charged, according to Discover. Their solution was to cancel my payment before setting up automatic payments, but instead, I'll just wait to set up automatic payments until my pill payment has successfully posted.

Speaking of Discover, a representative was supposed to initiate a dispute with my old domain registrar yesterday, then contact me. I received no such contact, so I contacted Discover about the matter today. As it turns out, the representative *did* initiate the dispute, but just had forgotten to contact me about it. Perfect. The gears are already turning and the dispute is in the works. The representative that I spoke with reminded me that the dispute will take thirty days (twenty-nine more) to resolve. I can only hope that this ends well and that I don't have to cancel my Discover account in order to stop paying my old domain registrar for services that I cannot access.

It seems that work on Replicant 6.0 has begun! Finally, we will soon be able to upgrade to a more modern system, which might even have more of the known security issues fixed. The catch, at least for me, is that the version beong worked on at the moment is only for the GT-i9300. If I hadn't allowed my old device to be stolen, I'd be closer to Replicant 6.0 than I am on my new GT-i9100M! This is a bit disheartening. It seems that Replicant 6.0 will have full device encryption, which I assume means that the operating system itself will be encrypted, as Replicant 4.2 already had full user storage encryption. It looks like Replicant is also trying to get F-Droid's repositories filtered to show only free applications by default, though they are deliberately not caring about non-free assets, which is one of the biggest problems in the F-Droid repository. F-Droid developers do seem to be building the required filters, and doing the only thing that could possibly make such a feature complete, they're allowing applications that any specific user doesn't like be filtered out on a per-user basis. All that it will take on my end is to select the NonFreeAssets filter and report applications that incorrectly don't have that flag set. For example, there is a game that I'm going to need to refind that doesn't have this flag set, but uses nonfree graphics.

While reading about University of [REDACTED]'s course requirements, I found that for eleven of the required courses, I must find a proctor to watch me take the course exam! I'm not allowed to pay the proctor, as it could be considered bribery, and I cannot be related to this person. I can hire a proctor service, in which case I am allowed to pay, but the recommended proctor service only allows one to use one of two proprietary operating systems and demands that Flash be installed. Ugh. That won't work. It looks like I'll be seeking volunteer proctors at some point. The university recommended local officials, librarians, supervisors from work, and religious figures for this task.

To help me organize my thoughts and understand what order I need to take courses in, I've arranged the required courses into a tree list based on their prerequisites:

CS 1101: Programming Fundamentals

CS 1102: Programming 1

CS 1103: Programming 2

CS 1104: Computer Systems

CS 2204: Communications and Networking

CS 4404: Advanced Networking and Data Security

CS 2205: Web Programming 1 (proctored course)

CS 3305: Web Programming 2 (Proctored course)
CS 4405: Mobile Applications

CS 2301: Operating Systems 1 (proctored course)

CS 3307: Operating Systems 2

CS 2401: Software Engineering 1

CS 4403: Software Engineering 2

CS 3303: Data Structures

CS 3304: Analysis of Algorithms

CS 4406: Computer Graphics (proctored course)
CS 4407: Data Mining and Machine Learning (proctored course)

CS 4408: Artificial Intelligence (proctored course)

CS 3308: Information Retrieval (proctored course)

CS 4402: Comparative Programming Languages

CS 2203: Databases 1

CS 3306: Databases 2 (proctored course)

ENGL 1102: English Composition 2 (proctored course)
HIST 1421: Greek and Roman Civilization
MATH 1302: Discrete Mathematics
MATH 1201: College Algebra (proctored course)

MATH 1211: Calculus

MATH 1280: Introduction to Statistics (proctored course)
PHIL 1404: Ethics and Social Responsibility
UNIV 1001: Online Education Strategies

There is a strange discrepancy though. Before I'm allowed to take any courses specific to my major, I'm required to take MATH 1201, MATH 1280, CS 1101, and CS 1102. However, CS 1101 and CS 1102 *are* specific to my major! Additionally, I have five elective courses and five courses that I need to take that aren't specific courses, but courses that I need to choose from small lists.

Any one of these:

BIOL 1121: Biology 1 for Health Studies Majors
BIOL 1301: Introduction to Biology
ENVS 1301: Introduction to Environmental Science

Any two of these:

ECON 1580: Introduction to Economics
POLS 1503: Globalization
PSYC 1111: Introduction to Human Psychology
PSYC 1205: Emotional Intelligence
PSYC 1504: Introduction to Psychology
SOC 1502: Introduction to Sociology

Any two of these:

AHIST 1401: Art History
ENGL 1405: World Literature
PHIL 1402: Introduction to Philosophy

Any five electives

The people that registered me for my first two courses just chose two without talking to me. Because they chose POLS 1503 as one of them, one of the optional courses above was already chosen for me. I'm not sure what to think of that, but I'll just go with it. As for next term, I think that it would be a good idea to take CS 1101, MATH 1201, and if I take a third course, MATH 1280. These three (along with CS 1102) are required before I can do much on the computer science side of things. If I can get as many prerequisites out of the way as soon as possible, I'll have a lot more flexibility as to when I choose to take other courses. The fourth course, CS 1102, depends on CS 1101, so I'll have to wait to take that one anyway. This also means even more that CS 1101 should be taken next term. Taking MATH 1201 also paves the way to taking MATH 1211, but that's much less urgent.

We took two more loads to the storage unit today. I'm hoping that we don't spend much time on that tomorrow though, as I want to get started on my schoolwork.

NotABug seems to be down, which is a bit frustrating. I hope that they're not gone for good, but they seem to have been down all day. Luckily, I have backups of my repositories at Volatile Git, but I'd rather have my repositories uploaded to two different places than only one. One can never be too careful, and services could die at any time.

Document modifications

On 2017-11-02, this journal page was modified in order to redact the name of the university and the link to their website.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.